Hello listeners, how are you doing today? Welcome back to Luke's English Podcast.
听众朋友们，今天过得怎么样？欢迎收听卢克英语播客。
Let me tell you what you can expect from this episode. So in the UK, in Britain,
在这期节目中，我将向大家介绍：在英国、英国本土，
on the BBC, on television, there's a really popular show and it's called Room 101.
在英国广播公司（BBC）的电视上，有一档非常受欢迎的节目，名为《101房间》。
It's a really popular show, it's the sort of thing that you see on maybe a Friday evening
这档节目非常受欢迎，类似周五晚上的娱乐节目。
or something like that. It's a comedy chat show. It's been on TV for many years
它是一档喜剧聊天节目，至今已在电视上播出多年，
and it's a really well-known show, lots of British people know Room 101.
且是英国最知名的品牌之一，大部分英国人都知道《101房间》。
The concept of the show is that there's the host and there's the guest. More recent iterations of
节目形式是主持人接待嘉宾，近年来的版本
the show, you see a host and three guests and they sort of compete with each other and stuff
会有主持人带领三位嘉宾展开竞争，类似这样的互动环节。
like that. But the basic idea is that a guest is invited onto the show and they name three things
但核心设定是：邀请嘉宾上台，请他们列出三个
which they would like to be removed from the world and banished into this room called Room 101.
希望从世界上消失并关进"101房间"的物品。
Now the idea of that is sort of loosely inspired by the story 1984 written by George Orwell,
该设定灵感源于乔治·奥威尔的小说《1984》，
which of course is a very serious book, a very important book. You might well have read it
这是一本非常重要且严肃的作品。相信许多朋友都读过。
and in that book there is a room which is called Room 101 and that's where all of your worst fears
书中提到的"101房间"存放着所有你最恐惧的事物，
and all of the things in the world that you are most afraid of and that you hate the most,
包括你最深恶痛恨的世界万物。这就是你绝对不希望被带去的噩梦房间。
they're all in Room 101. So it's like your nightmare room that you never want to be taken to.
因此《101房间》的灵感正源于此。但在这档喜剧节目中，
So that's where the idea of Room 101 came from. But in this TV show,
我们看到喜剧演员、演员、明星等各行业知名嘉宾云集，
which is a comedy show with famous guests from all sorts of different lines of work,
他们同样会被要求提出三个希望被驱逐到"101房间"的事物。
a lot of comedians and actors and celebrities and stuff are invited on.
通俗来说，就是他们想从世界上清除的三样东西。
And yes, they name three things that they would like to be banished into Room 101.
过往节目中嘉宾们提出的各种案例，或许可以让你了解
So essentially three things they want to remove from the world. And some of the things that
《101房间》曾探讨过哪些话题。比如不捡拾宠物粪便的人，
people have talked about on the show over the years, maybe I can give you a sense of what
这显然是所有人都会认同应该被关进房间的对象。
has been included in previous episodes of Room 101. People who don't pick up their dog's poo,
不捡拾宠物粪便的人。天啊，这简直太可笑了。
which is obviously definitely something everyone will agree should go into Room 101.
类似还有试穿衣服带来的麻烦，比如进商店试衣服
People who don't pick up their dog's poo. I mean, that's awful. Also things like trying on clothes,
这种需要花时间挑选衣物的繁琐过程。
like the inconvenience of having to go into a shop and to try on the clothes.
包括你最深恶痛恨的世界万物。这就是你绝对不希望被带去的噩梦房间。
You have to wait at the fitting room and then you have to get your clothes
你需要在试衣间等待，然后脱下衣服，但那个小帘子总是关不严实，整个过程很不方便。
off and the little curtain doesn't close properly and it's all very inconvenient.
最后你觉得这衣服简直糟透了，但还是不买了。
And at the end you decide it looks terrible. You don't buy it anyway.
试穿衣服是那些讨论试穿衣服的人之一——艾丽丝·莱文，我觉得她是英国广播电台和电视台的主持人。
Trying on clothes is one of the things who said who talked about trying on clothes. Alice Levine,
电话这类我们不得不应付的烦心事。
I think, who is a an English radio and television presenter. Also phone calls,
餐厅里的面包。我不太明白餐厅面包的问题，
which arguably are annoying things we all have to do.
但有位名人提到假装受伤的足球运动员。我们都同意这种事很烦人。
Bread in restaurants. I don't know what the problem with bread in restaurants is,
衣架，你知道那些金属挂钩用来挂外套的。
but one of the celebrities mentioned that football
这些衣架啊，我完全能理解为什么人们想扔掉它们。
players who pretend to be injured. We can all agree that's annoying.
它们容易变形，会散架，甚至掉到地上。
Coat hangers, you know, those metal wire things that we use to hang our coats up in
还有什么？比如养猫、新年夜、有人过马路时不停让行却不道谢，
the cupboard. Those coat hangers, yeah, I could understand why we would want to get rid of them
对吧？这些都是生活中、这个星球上让我们想永远剔除的烦心事。
because they're so annoying. They bend, they fall apart, they fall on the floor, things like that.
《101房间》这个电视节目的概念就是如此。本集我们就来实现这个创意。
What else have we got? Cats, New Year's Eve, people who don't say thank you to you when
在播客里用《101房间》的形式进行讨论，因为这是创建幽默对话和让嘉宾吐槽讨厌之事的绝佳方式。
you stop to let them cross the road at a zebra crossing and things like that,
今天我的嘉宾是英国英语播客的主持人查理·巴斯特。
right? So it's normally kind of not too serious, just annoying things about life,
在各大播客平台都能收听到《英国英语播客》，所以查理会作为嘉宾参与。
about the world that we would like to be banished forever in Room 101. That's
他选了三个话题，而我会担任主持人，我的任务是倾听查理的倾诉。
the concept of the TV show. Now in this episode, that's what we're going to do.
最终裁定他提出的这些烦心事是否应该被扔进《101房间》。
We're going to take the idea of Room 101 and do it on the podcast because
餐厅里的面包。我不太明白餐厅面包的问题，
it's basically a good fun way to create some humorous conversation and to let a guest rant
但有位名人提到假装受伤的足球运动员。我们都同意这种事很烦人。
about some things that they don't like or to complain about some things that are annoying
衣架，你知道那些金属挂钩用来挂外套的。
or have caused them trouble in their life, okay? And my guest today is Charlie Baxter,
这些衣架啊，我完全能理解为什么人们想扔掉它们。
the host of the British English Podcast. The British English Podcast,
它们容易变形，会散架，甚至掉到地上。
wherever you get your podcasts, you can listen to it. So Charlie is going to be my guest.
还有什么？比如养猫、新年夜、有人过马路时不停让行却不道谢，
He's chosen three things to talk about and I'm going to be the host and it's my job to listen
对吧？这些都是生活中、这个星球上让我们想永远剔除的烦心事。
to Charlie and ultimately to judge whether the things he's brought will be thrown into Room
《101房间》这个电视节目的概念就是如此。本集我们就来实现这个创意。
101 or not. So it's up to me to decide that, okay? I'll let you discover the three things
101还是不101，这得由我决定，行吧？我会让你们揭晓查理选中的三个关键点。
that Charlie has chosen. They're quite specific things and I think you're going to enjoy this.
这些是查理精心挑选的特定事项，我认为你们会喜欢的。
There's one in particular, one thing in particular here that,
其中有个特别的东西，嗯，
well, I think it could create some YouTube drama. I think there could be some YouTube drama here.
这可能会引发YouTube争议事件，我认为这里确实存在争议可能。
I'm not normally someone who goes in for that kind of thing, but Charlie chose to, let's say,
我通常不参与这类事，但查理选择讲述一个你们可能熟悉的人的故事——某位英语教学领域最具影响力的YouTube频道主。
tell a story about a particular person that you might know, a particular YouTube English teacher,
可能是位英国英语女YouTuber？涉及她的某个戏剧性事件，我会让你们自己发现。
maybe the biggest, one of the biggest, maybe the biggest English teaching YouTube channel.
这件事足够让网络炸开锅了，我确信会引发热议。
Who could that be? British English, female British YouTuber teaching
究竟是哪位？
English. There's some drama relating to her and I'll let you discover it,
英国英语女性YouTuber？英语教学领域？她涉及的事件我会让你们揭晓。
okay? I'm sure it's going to break the internet. I'm sure it will.
行吧？这绝对会引爆网络。
I'll let you discover that. We're going to start in just a second. I should also
同样，我会让你们发现的。接下来我们将开始。
say that Charlie and I have chosen to do a sort of swap cast this week.
我需要补充的是本周我们采用嘉宾互换形式录制。
As you know, Charlie's the guest on Luke's English podcast today, but also I will be
如你所知，查理是卢克英语播客的嘉宾，而本周我也会以嘉宾身份参与。
the guest as I smash my microphone, I will be the guest on the British English podcast this
我会在英国英语播客中担任嘉宾，并带来激情主持。
week. So if you listen to this week's episode of the British English podcast,
本周英国英语播客的听众将听到我的客串，并见证我选中的三个"101禁入项"。
you will hear me as the guest and I've chosen my three things that I would like to be banished
具体是哪三项，请收听完整版了解。
into room 101. I will let you listen to that episode to discover what those three things are.
英国英语播客可通过常规平台收听，本集剧集描述里会有专属链接。
The British English podcast, you'll find it wherever you get your podcast.
此外官网有配套电子版PDF，包含完整字幕文本。
And I will put a link in the episode description for this episode. What
该PDF将帮助巩固听力收获，便于复习语言细节。
else do I need to add? Just that there is an episode PDF for this on the website.
本集内容语言丰富，包含大量地道表达和优质词汇。
You'll find that linked in the description as well. On the PDF, you'll see a full episode
由于两位主持人即兴发挥热烈，听众将听到大量实用表达。
transcript. So if you want to like read it later in order to just kind of consolidate some of
因此我们特别准备了这个学习资料包。
the things you've heard to notice some bits of language, because it's very rich with language.
点击剧集描述即可获取所有资源，包含：
This episode, Charlie and I just, we really got on a roll here and you'll notice lots
完整中英文字幕对照版
of different expressions and nice bits of vocabulary. So if that's your thing,
关键表达词汇表
if you're a vocab hunter, if you're always looking for nice bits of English vocabulary, there's
如果你是个词汇猎人，如果你总是在寻找优美的英语词汇片段，本集中有大量值得注意和学习的精彩内容。
plenty for you to notice and pick up in this episode. The transcript will help you to do that.
网易云课堂会提供完整版文字稿，帮助你更高效地学习这些内容。
I suggest that you just listen to the episode and then maybe look at the transcript again,
我建议你先完整收听这期节目，之后可以结合文字稿反复研读，
read through it. And that's where you can actually look at picking out bits of vocab that you can,
这时就能找出值得收藏的实用词汇，你懂的，未来可以自己学习和使用这些词汇。
you know, learn and use yourself in the future. Okay.
好的。
So you'll find a link for the PDF transcript in the
需要的话，可以在节目描述里找到PDF文字稿的链接。
episode description as well. Right then. So without any further ado, let's get started.
那我们直接开始吧。
Let's get into this conversation with Charlie Baxter. So this is
接下来让我们与Charlie Baxter展开对话。
Room 101 on Luke's English Podcast with Charlie Baxter. And here we go.
这是卢克英语播客《101房间》与Charlie Baxter的特别对谈。
Conversation
对话
Charlie, I'm very curious to find out what your three things are that you've chosen to banish from
Charlie，我很好奇你准备将哪些事物列入需要从世界清除的三项清单。
the world. Um, yes. Was this easy for you? Was it easy for you to, to come up with three things?
嗯，这个过程困难吗？
It's interesting. It was actually kind of therapeutic in the sense that if something
是的，很有趣。
bad goes wrong, you're like, “you're going in room 101” and you're like, ah, that's,
当不好的事发生时，你总说“去101房间”，这让我感到安慰，仿佛那些烦恼被消灭了。
that's nice. So that gets rid of that in my imagination. But then also I started thinking,
但后来我也开始思考，
Oh, is there, are there better things that I should be looking for? And you start,
是否应该寻找更有价值的目标？
and I'm starting to look for the bad things in life a bit too much.
我发现自己开始过于关注生活中的负面事物了。
You're not normally that way inclined are you? You're more
你通常不是这样吗？
of a sort of the glass is half full type of person. I would imagine.
你应该是个乐观派，属于“杯满半满论”吧？
When the sun is out, I'm very optimistic. Yeah. When it's raining and I feel like I've made poor
出太阳时你总很积极，
choices to be stuck in the rain, then, uh, yeah, I could be a little bit moany, a little bit moany.
下雨时如果觉得自己选错了待在雨中的位置，
And I think it's been raining quite a
你就会抱怨两句。
lot recently. So maybe you've come up with a lot of ideas.
最近雨确实下得比较多，
I've come up with quite a list. I've had to narrow them down. I've had to decide,
所以你应该想了不少候选清单。
you know, which goes where.
我列了很长的清单，最后得精简筛选出前三项。
And, um, yeah, I wonder whether you think I should go for the, the bigger ones. Well,
嗯，我有点犹豫，我应该选更大的那些吗？好吧，
they're not that big. They're all pretty small, actually all little things in life.
其实并没有想象中那么大。其实都是生活中那些微不足道的小事。
It's not like, um, you know, the Royal family or politics in general,
和英国王室或政治界那些大事无关，比如说政客们。
politicians. No, it's quite, quite small things, but yeah.
不，都是些很小的事，不过 yeah，
Okay. Yeah. That's, that's quite common. I think for room 101, uh, often it's just
好的。 yeah，这很常见。101号牢房通常就是些鸡毛蒜皮的小烦心事，比如些烦人的、恼人的小事。
like little petty annoying, annoying things, little irritating things.
嗯，你可以先选一个，不过我们先开始吧。先说说你的第一个烦恼。没错，我就是判官，对吧？由我决定是否拉动手柄，把这个烦恼永远关进101号牢房。
Uh, you can decide, you can decide which one you go with first, but,
（重复）嗯，可以自行选择顺序，但
uh, let's, let's begin. Tell us your first thing. And I can, I'm going to be the judge, right? I
（重复）先开始吧。请说出你的第一个烦恼。没错，我就是审判者，我决定是否真的要拉动手柄，把这个烦恼永远关进101号牢房。
get to decide whether in fact I will pull the lever and send this thing into room 101 forever.
绝对同意。 yeah。
Absolutely. Yeah. Okay.
请讲。
So go ahead.
你有选择权。 yeah。
You get the power. Yeah.
嗯，这个烦恼其实就发生在上周，我还在犹豫是否要公开。我们看看吧。不过这个
Um, so this one actually comes with a story that's happened very recently and
问题非常具体。当你去公共卫生间，看到有纸巾分发机，但
I'm not sure if I'm ready to expose it, uh, live on air, but we'll see. But the,
无法通过任何方式判断纸巾存量。
the problem is very specific. It's when you go into a bathroom, a public bathroom and,
因为纸巾卷是金属外壳的，看不到内部情况。
um, and then you, you see that there's a dispenser and there's toilet paper,
哇，太具体了。场景就是公共厕所。
but you cannot detect how much toilet paper there is because it's not transparent in any way.
有个纸巾分发机在隔间里，但
Wow. This is so specific. So it's in a public toilet.
外壳不透明，金属材质的。
It's a toilet paper dispenser. So you've gone into a cubicle to do your business. There's a,
所以你不知道纸巾卷里到底剩下多少。
there's a toilet paper dispenser in there, but it is not transparent.
right，就是这种情况。你进隔间解决问题时，里面放着不透明的纸巾分发机。
It's made of metal or something. And so you don't know how much toilet paper
纸巾卷是金属外壳包装的，完全看不见存量。
is actually contained with inside the, inside the role of toilet paper. Right.
所以你不知道里面到底剩下多少卷纸。
Okay. Yeah. Because then you don't know what ratio you've,
对，所以你不知道剩余比例。
you've got and, and you know, how to, how sparing you should be with each piece.
也不会知道该用多少，每张纸都要省着用。
I mean, obviously, you know, we don't want to waste paper. That'd be terrible,
毕竟，我们肯定不希望浪费纸张，那太糟糕了。
but you know, you don't want to. Yeah.
但说实话，你其实并不想呢。嗯。
You got, you got a more, there's a more pressing immediate concern when
你知道，你更担心的是，刚在厕所做完事后，还有更紧迫的即时问题。
you've just done whatever you've done in the toilet. Obviously you're thinking of
你肯定在想着环境问题。我不想浪费太多纸，但也觉得必须彻底完成任务。
the environment. I don't want to use too much paper, but also you're thinking,
是啊。这就让我陷入焦虑。每次拉完都问：
I don't want to leave this toilet cubicle, uh, without having finished the job fully.
这是不是最后一次？彻底解决了吗？彻底解决了吗？哎。
Yeah. And so, yeah, it puts me in a state of paranoia. Every pull it's like,
就像每天都要面对死亡威胁的感觉。
is that the last one? Is that it? Is that it? Oh yeah.
是吧？是不是最后一次？彻底了吗？彻底了吗？哎。
It's like thinking that you're going to die every single day.
就像每天都要面对死亡威胁。
Yeah. I'm sure it's exactly like that.
是这样的没错。
Yeah. I'm sure it says quite, you never know. Your doctor has said,
的确，医生说过：
look, it could happen any day now.
"随时都可能发生。"
In fact, you could die any moment. I mean, it's, you know, that's your
事实上，任何时刻都可能发生。就是说，
doctor doesn't need to say that. I mean, you to technically any of us could die at any time.
医生根本没必要说这个。毕竟我们任何人都可能随时离世。
You know, we don't, we never know when a,
我们永远不知道下次陨石撞击是什么时候，
when an asteroid is going to, you know, hit the earth or something.
有时候我还会想那些小行星的事呢。嗯。
Uh, I sometimes think about that asteroids. Yeah.
它们说没就出现，然后我们全完了。很可能。
Just, it could just out of nowhere and that's us
我的意思是，总有一天会发生这种事吧？嗯，我知道。
all gone. Probably will. I mean, it probably will at some point.
我记得统计数据显示，绕地球飞行的小行星数量，
I mean, it's going to be something like that, isn't this eventually? I mean, you know, I've,
加上它们与地球相撞的概率，
I've heard that if, you know, statistically the number of asteroids flying around and,
以及历史上发生过的次数，我们早该等待一次大型撞击了。没错。
um, you know, the, the, the likelihood of one striking the earth and the number of
因为它们每天都在出现。小行星不断进入大气层。嗯。
times it's happened in the past, we're kind of do we're overdue an asteroid. Yeah. A big one.
(停顿) 小行星... Yeah。
Because they happen every single day. Like little ones constantly come into our atmosphere. Yeah.
但关键是大型的！ Yeah。
That's …little ones. Yeah. They're fine.
小型的不算。 Yeah。
Yeah. But it's the big ones. Yeah.
关键是大型的！ Yeah。
That's the, that's the trouble. But anyway, back to, back to more important concerns,
那就是那个问题。不过咱们还是回到更重要的事情上吧，
which is where, yeah, you've gone into the toilet cubicle and the
就是说你进了厕所隔间后遇到的那个具体问题，
specific problem is you don't know how much toilet paper there is inside this
你根本不知道这个容器里到底有多少卫生纸。
thing. And so what is it exactly that you want to be banished into room 101?
那么你到底想把这个东西被流放到101号房间？
I want the transparency to be a governing rule.
我希望透明原则成为最高准则。
That is the material, the material that needs to hold the dispenser or hold the
也就是需要支撑纸盒或承载纸张的材质，
paper needs to be, it absolutely needs to be transparent. Like there's no way that it,
必须完全透明。绝对不能让我们看不见可用量。
it can be allowed that we can't see how much we've got to play with. Right.
我们不能允许自己不知道可用的数量对吧？
So opaque toilet dispensers need to be banished.
所以不透明式厕所纸盒必须被淘汰。
Yes. That's the ones that you can't see. You can't see through non-see-through toilet
是的。就是那些你看不透的。
paper dispensers. This is specifically the thing that you want removed from the world.
非透明材质的厕所纸盒。这正是你希望从世界上消失的东西。
That is, that is that, but to, to counter it. Because I do understand
就是说...不过要考虑到，
that being a public bathroom, you want to have it securely fastened so that nobody,
公共卫生间需要安全固定防止有人，
you know, I don't know if they do do this, but I imagine that some
我不知道他们会不会这么做，但推测可能有人会进去...
might go in there and take the whole roll. So you've got to have it securely locked. Right.
所以必须锁起来对吧？
So which, and, and, and, uh, strong. So that's perhaps why they are sometimes
所以需要...需要更强的材质，
made of metal to avoid someone just ripping it open and going, I'm taking all this toilet
这可能就是为什么它们有时用金属制成，
paper and to hell with the world. I need to wipe my bum at home as well as in public.
以防有人撕开包装说"全拿走好了，管他世界怎样，我回家也要用"。
I mean, you know, I'm sure people do steal the toilet
毕竟人们确实会偷卫生纸。
paper. Of course they do. Uh, but you know, yeah.
当然会。呃，不过你想想，
Okay. You know, what's even worse though, sorry to interrupt is when
更糟糕的是当它们透明但有机械装置，
they are see-through and there's this sort of mechanism that there's one stored up there,
里面有个备用卷轴但无法取出时，
but you can't access it. Like they've got a backup one.
就像厂家偷偷加了备用卷。
And it happened to me the other day. Um, and I actually, yeah.
前几天我就遇到了这种情况。呃，确实。
Do you want me to tell you the story?
你想听我讲故事吗？
Oh, please, please do.
请求你，求你了。
So I've new to Porto, just moved here recently to Portugal.
我刚搬到葡萄牙的波尔图，才三个月左右。
Yeah. Porto in Portugal.
是的，葡萄牙的波尔图。
I was in London for the last three years, drove down.
上个月还在伦敦待了三年，开车过来的。
Um, it's been raining ever since there was one sunny day on the weekend where my wife and I,
自从上周六我们夫妇去海边散步那天下雨后，
we went to the coast, went to, uh, Foz and, uh, enjoyed a lovely brunch and a beach walk
我们去了福兹（Foz），带狗子吃了顿美味的早午餐，
with our dog. Um, but on that beach walk after the brunch, I started to get some stomach cramps and,
散步时我的肚子突然开始抽筋，
uh, I started to complain to Stacey and she was like, Oh, get over it. It's fine.
我跟史蒂西抱怨，她却说"别矫情了，没事的"。
And then I was like, actually at points I was like, no,
可我确实觉得，
this is actually really bad. I might have to just do it here. Like right now.
这情况太严重了，现在就得解决。
She was like, don't be silly. I got over it. And then 30 minutes later, we were walking
她却说"傻话，忍忍就好"。
towards some toilets and she then said, Oh, I need a, a wee, I'll go and use the bathroom.
30分钟后我们走到公共厕所，
So I was like, okay, yeah, fine. And then we've got there, there were two
她突然说"我得尿尿，去洗手间"。
toilets. One was occupied, two people were standing near it.
我看到两个厕所：
The other one wasn't. So she went in, but she was like, it doesn't lock. It's not like registering.
一个有人在使用，另个空着。
So I was like, Oh, I'll just stand out here. That's fine. And then when she was in there,
她先进了那个没锁的，
my stomach started going and I was like, ah, okay,
我刚坐下肚子又疼了，
can you hurry up please? Um, something's happening.
就喊"你能快点吗？呃，情况不对劲了"。
And then the other people next to us, they went and I was like, okay, do I sacrifice my wife's
旁边的人也进洗手间了，
dignity by leaving an open door or do I go at, or do I just wait here and see what happens?
我纠结要不要为妻子的尊严离开空门，
Oh, because you were standing there holding the door closed for your wife. Meanwhile,
或者继续等，又或者自己冲进去？
one of the other cubicles became available and you had a moral decision to make. What is,
因为当时你正挡着门等妻子，
what's more important? My, my underpants or my wife? Yeah.
这时另一个隔间空出来了，
And, uh, it's a difficult decision. It's a very difficult decision. Yeah.
你面临艰难抉择：
My wife is more important to me. I'll leave it.
我的裤衩重要还是老婆重要？嗯？
That's the correct answer, Charlie.
这是正确答案，查理。
But you know what? That wasn't the worst of it. So that happened. I was like,
但你知道吗？这还没到最糟糕的部分。事情发生了。我当时心想，
Oh, did you actually, sorry. Did you follow through?
你真做了？抱歉。你坚持到最后了吗？
Yeah. Yeah. Oh dear.
是的。是的。天啊。
Oh my God. Disaster. I haven't done that in like 15 years probably.
天哪。灾难。十五年前我就没干过这种事了。
Um, I have done that. But 15 years ago…
我做过。但十五年前……
There's another story there. I was thinking he's not that he's not,
还有个故事。我原以为他没那么年轻。查理还年轻，但没那么年轻。他十五年前还穿尿布呢。除非有什么我不知情的医学状况。
he's not that young. Charlie's young, but he's not that young. It's not like 15 years since he
不过算了。总之，那已经是多年前的事了。你上次在裤裆里搞出紧急情况是什么时候？
was wearing nappies. Um, unless there was some, you know, other medical condition I'm unaware of.
我透过门缝小声说：'快一点！我尿裤子了。'
But, um, anyway, okay. It's been a long time since that happened since
她说好的好的好的。出去后我冲进去，手忙脚乱不太懂运作机制。
you had an emergency in your, in your underpants like that.
她说："锁住了。"然后开始自动清洁。
So I was whispering through the doors, like, can you hurry up? I've just shat myself.
公共厕所进入清洁模式。
And she's like, okay, okay, okay. She goes out and then I go in,
是的。这种未来感十足的公共厕所，带有电子锁和自清洁系统。
rush in. Don't really understand the mechanism.
结果怎样？我的丁字裤卡在脚踝上，刚坐下就朝我的后部喷水。
And she's like, Oh, it's locked. And then it starts cleaning itself.
这倒算不上坏事，但水雾太弥散了，不够精准。
So the public toilet goes into cleaning mode.
我突然弹起来，往角落躲。四个角突然弹出喷水嘴，把我的裤子喷湿了。
Yeah. So it's one of those futuristic toilets that kind of has an electric, an
我站在原地。此时你不该在马桶里。它正处于清洁模式中，
electric lock on the door and then a self cleaning system after it's been used. Okay.
还有个故事。我原以为他没那么年轻。查理还年轻，但没那么年轻。他十五年前还穿尿布呢。除非有什么我不知情的医学状况。
And what happens? Because I had my boxers round my ankles. I
不过算了。总之，那已经是多年前的事了。你上次在裤裆里搞出紧急情况是什么时候？
was going to sit down and it starts shooting water up into my rear end,
我透过门缝小声说：'快一点！我尿裤子了。'
which is kind of in a way good, but it was misty. It was not directional enough.
她说好的好的好的。出去后我冲进去，手忙脚乱不太懂运作机制。
And then, and then I sort of sit up suddenly I'm like, Oh God,
她说："锁住了。"然后开始自动清洁。
I shimmy over to the corner away from this mist. And then these little pop-up
公共厕所进入清洁模式。
sprinklers come from each corner and they jet my trousers. So I'm stood there.
是的。这种未来感十足的公共厕所，带有电子锁和自清洁系统。
So you shouldn't be in the toilet at this point. It's in cleaning mode and
结果怎样？我的丁字裤卡在脚踝上，刚坐下就朝我的后部喷水。
the human being is not supposed to be in there while it cleans itself. Okay.
人类不应在清洁过程中进入该区域。好的。
So you're standing there. It's just sprayed, maybe soapy water all over
所以你当时站在那里，全身都喷满了肥皂水
your trousers. And you've just been misted with some sort of soapy detergent.
你的裤子上还沾着泡沫清洁剂
Yeah, exactly. And then the dust settles and then I go and sit down,
对，然后灰尘落定后我就坐下
do my business. And then I go to get some toilet paper out and it's a non-transparent thing.
做我的事。接着去拿卫生纸，那是个不透明的卷纸机
I use a few and then it runs out. And I'm like,
用了些许，但突然就用完了。我真是
I could do with 90% more than what I've just used. That is terrible.
急需90%的补充量。这设计太差劲了
Okay. I see. I feel like you're, I feel like you're focusing all of the,
好的。我明白。感觉你把所有注意力
um, uh, all of your attention on the toilet roll dispenser.
全部集中在卷纸机的按钮上
And there's a whole other range of things that could have been the focal point or
但这个故事真正的问题焦点
faecal point maybe, of this whole story. Don't you think? That of all the things
或者说是核心矛盾，可能另有玄机
that have gone wrong in this situation that it seems to be just like the final straw,
难道不该思考下吗？在众多故障中
maybe that's, maybe that's what it is. Yeah.
这只是压垮骆驼的最后一根稻草？
I mean, that, that thing has come up before. So
或许如此。这种问题我之前遇到过
it was like a good reminder for me that that is a thing. Okay.
算是给我敲响警钟。嗯
So, so you've got history with this kind of, with those toilet roll dispensers. Okay. And so after
你跟卷纸机有历史渊源？对
all of this, you're like, “and the toilet roll dispenser, I can't judge how much paper there is.”
所以现在你心想："这卷纸机根本无法判断存量"
Yeah. And you ran out, you ran out of paper. Yeah.
是的，纸用完了
You didn't know. So if you'd been able to, would it have made a difference if
你当时完全不知情。如果
you'd been able to see through the toilet roll dispenser, if you'd known exactly how
如果能透过卷纸机看到存量
much paper there was, would that made a, would that have made a difference?
清楚知道纸够用的话，情况会不同吗？
That's a good question. And the answer is probably it would have been worse
这是个好问题。答案可能是更糟
because I would have been fearing the end all the way through the process.
因为你会全程焦虑纸会耗尽
Yeah. Because I would have been able to know that this is not enough for what I need. So I'm
是的，这样提前知晓不足
buggered, but, um, my wife did help me because she went to the other toilet and she got some
我就会陷入困境，不过好在我老婆及时帮忙
paper and then she gave it to me because my cubicle was in self-cleaning mode and then
她把文件递给我，因为我工位处于自清洁模式，随后门锁自动解开，所以门就打开了。
it released the lock. So it was open. So she was able to access the door and then she kind of got,
她得以进入，后来似乎觉得无聊，牵着狗离开了。谢谢。
um, bored and like walked off with the dog. Thanks.
是的。就是说，“查理，你又拉肚子了，真没劲。”
Yeah. I mean, you know, “Charlie, you know, shat himself again. How boring.”
有人尝试开门。这时有个陌生人出现了，卷入了这场状况？没错。
And, um, and so then somebody tried to open the door. A stranger turned
我说，您不想进来吧？因为门会自动清洁，建议您离开。
up a stranger, uh, arrived into the equation, into the situation too? Yeah.
我猜这种情况经常发生——当人们进出门时，若门未处于清洁模式，
So I was like, you don't want to come in here. You
他们完成工作、冲马桶后离开，门会自动锁闭并清洁，随后重新开启。
might want to leave it cause it will clean itself. Yeah.
有时流程会混乱。比如您先进去时门在清洁模式，
I wonder how often that happens that people, you know, the order gets all confused because if the,
等您出来后，另一个人进去又遇到同样情况，
if, if the, so you, a person goes in, it's not in cleaning mode,
两人交替进入时，清洁程序可能出错。
they do their thing, they finish, they flush the toilet, they leave, and then the toilet
您出来后门已清洁完毕重新开启，但另一个人进来时又重复相同流程。
locks and cleans itself. And then it becomes open. Maybe sometimes the order goes all wrong.
这种循环往复容易让人困惑。
And if you've been in there in cleaning mode and then you go,
最后问题出在两人互相认识却未关闭门的情况——
it, you, you, you, you, you, you, you, you wait, it's confusing. You get out and then
当门反复开合时，他们误以为对方已离开，
the other person comes in, then they're in there in cleaning mode as well, no?
误触清洁程序导致系统混乱。
Uh, anyway. I think the issue is if two people like know each other and
因此责任不在门本身，而在于纸盒机未明确显示剩余纸量。
they leave the door open and the other person goes in because the door opens,
正是这点设计缺陷让人误操作。
closes, and then opens and closes. And then they think, okay, that person's out.
所以我不怪门，怪的是纸盒机没标明纸量。
I can clean. Do you know what I mean?
是的，您说得对。
You screwed up the system by misunderstanding the electric door and holding it.
两人交替进入时，清洁程序可能出错。
For that reason, I'm not angry at it. I'm angry at the dispenser.
您出来后门已清洁完毕重新开启，但另一个人进来时又重复相同流程。
Right. I see. Because you, so you take responsibility for all the other things,
这种循环往复容易让人困惑。
but the, the, the, yeah, but it's the dispenser not showing you how
最后问题出在两人互相认识却未关闭门的情况——
much paper. That's the, that's the main problem. Yeah. I see.
当门反复开合时，他们误以为对方已离开，
Yeah. I mean, actually the main problem should be food poisoning.
误触清洁程序导致系统混乱。
If you're a restaurant, don't give food poisoning to your customers. Yeah. To be fair.
如果你是餐厅，就不要给顾客食物中毒。好吧。说句公道话。
Yeah. That's the root of the problem,
好吧。问题的根源就在于此，
isn't it? Whatever it was that you ate that your stomach disagreed with.
不是吗？就是因为你吃了某些让胃部不适的东西。
Okay. I'm now trying to decide. So opaque or non-see-through toilet roll dispensers,
好吧。我现在在纠结。不透明的卷纸机和非透明卷纸机，
will they go into room 101 or not? See, the problem is that there's a sort of
它们会被安置在101号房间吗？问题是这些金属卷纸机在美观层面有优势，
cosmetic side to this, which is that those metal toilet roll dispensers look pretty good. I mean,
毕竟它们看起来挺不错的，而且能清楚看到纸巾存量。
they look quite nice, you know, and it's being able to see the amount of toilet paper.
这有它的好处，但另一方面，
Okay. It has its advantages, but at the same time,
我真的不希望每个厕所都摆着难看的卷纸机，知道吗？
I don't really want ugly toilet roll dispensers in every toilet, you know?
我对你在生活美学细节上的肤浅态度感到惊讶。好吧，
I'm very surprised at how superficial you're being with this particular element of your
你知道，我对自己的排泄系统有掌控权。
life that needs to be aesthetic. Well, you know, I have control over my bowels.
所以优先级是马桶的外观。不过换作你，
So, you know, this is the priority of like, just what does the toilet look like? But then again,
可能应该多体谅你的处境。但重点不在于你是否掌控排泄，
maybe I should be more sympathetic to someone in your position. But it's not
而是你是否需要纸巾。
about whether you have control over your bowels. It's whether you need toilet paper.
我假设你需要，是的，我需要。
And I assume the answer is yes. Yes, I do. Yeah, of course.
你不是特别严谨。作为家长，我总随身带纸巾或湿巾，
You're not that neat. As a parent, I always have some kind of tissues
以备不时之需。
or wipes on me at all times. So there’s always the backup.
但不可否认，公共厕所的纸巾确实很重要，
But yeah, no, I can't deny the importance of toilet paper in a public toilet. I mean,
这是谁都无法否认的。所以或许我该考虑
that just obviously can't be denied. So maybe I just
时刻带着纸巾或湿巾。
thought maybe I need to carry toilet wipes or something on me at all times.
但说实话，责任不全在你身上。
Yeah, but I don't know if the responsibility lies entirely with you. I mean, you know,
你知道，公共厕所本应是基本设施，
a public toilet, you'd imagine it's basic - one of
其中一项基本要求就是提供纸巾。
the basic requirements of a toilet is that there is toilet paper in it.
尽管有些国家可能连卷纸都不提供，
Although in some countries, they don't. You know, some places they just have like a little tap,
就像有些地方只有小喷头或水管，
a little hose with water. You're supposed to spray your bum with it or use your hand.
你得用流水冲洗或用手处理。
Yeah, my grandparents, I used to live in their house. When they passed away, we came back from
嗯，我爷爷奶奶，我曾经住 их доме。他们去世后我们从澳大利亚回来，当时还在协商谁要来买房。所以我们暂时住在那里，直到我们在伦敦找到新居。他们家浴室里有两台，你念 bidet 还是 bidet？Bidet。Bidet。好的，两个浴室都装了 bidet，我刚开始不太习惯，但后来倒适应了。
Australia and it was still being sorted out who was going to buy it from them. So we lived in
其实我还挺喜欢这个的。用水清洁确实更实用。我觉得很多听众也会认同，用卫生纸冲厕所挺不环保的，用水既高效又好保护环境，而且不用大量浪费厕纸。
there before we found a place in London and they had a, do you pronounce it bidet or bidet? Bidet.
可能我该等清洁模式重新激活再充分利用喷头功能。不过当时没预料到，确实措手不及。
Bidet. Okay. They had a bidet in both bathrooms and I got on board with that.
你不知道对吧？确实。
I loved it actually. I found it really useful. So I like the water approach.
对于你现在的处境，我决定同情你，查理。我要在房间101安装透明卷纸盒，这样你没法提前规划如厕时间。出于对你的怜悯，查理，我要在房间101执行这个惩罚。
I'm very for that because I think a lot of people listening would be like,
所以我要拉下拉杆，卷纸盒即将进入房间101。
it's gross to use toilet paper. Water is much more efficient. And also better for
到货了，正合适地铺在房间101的地面上。
the environment and not flushing all that paper down the toilet.
恭喜你获得首个透明卷纸盒。谢谢配合。
Maybe I should have waited until the cleaning mode activated again and sort of
干得漂亮！非常满意这个改进方案，多谢关照。
utilise the spray a bit better. Yeah, but you didn't know. It took you by surprise.
所以接下来第二个改造方案更劲爆，要爆料给某个YouTuber看。哦？这涉及YouTube内部 drama？
So you didn't know, did you? True.
就是那个视频创作者的负面新闻。确实是个爆料事件。
I don't know what to do. I don't know if I should… Out of sympathy for you, Charlie,
这需要简单解释下，"爆料"这个词其实和前面故事有呼应——就是公开他人隐私、传播负面信息。
and your predicament there, I think I'm going to agree and I'm going to put non-see-through toilet
我们必须明确这个概念。本质上就是公开他人丑闻、散布不当言论。
roll dispensers that don't allow you to plan ahead with your toilet visit. I'm going to put that into
Yeah, exactly. 比如说在之前的案例中，我们就是通过揭露不道德行为来解决问题。
room 101, Charlie, just out of pure sympathy for the terrible situation that you found yourself in.
其实我还挺喜欢这个的。用水清洁确实更实用。我觉得很多听众也会认同，用卫生纸冲厕所挺不环保的，用水既高效又好保护环境，而且不用大量浪费厕纸。
So I'm going to pull the lever and the toilet roll dispenser is going to enter room 101.
可能我该等清洁模式重新激活再充分利用喷头功能。不过当时没预料到，确实措手不及。
There it is. Landed onto the bottom of room 101. Okay.
你不知道对吧？确实。
So congratulations. You got your first one in. Thank you.
对于你现在的处境，我决定同情你，查理。我要在房间101安装透明卷纸盒，这样你没法提前规划如厕时间。出于对你的怜悯，查理，我要在房间101执行这个惩罚。
Very happy with that. Appreciate it. Very kind.
所以我要拉下拉杆，卷纸盒即将进入房间101。
Yes. So what about the second thing then? So the second thing is also a bit of a story attached
到货了，正合适地铺在房间101的地面上。
to it and it's dishing the dirt on a YouTuber, actually. Oh yeah? This is a bit of YouTube drama.
恭喜你获得首个透明卷纸盒。谢谢配合。
It is, actually. Yeah. Dishing the dirt.
干得漂亮！非常满意这个改进方案，多谢关照。
We need to explain that one. I mean,
所以接下来第二个改造方案更劲爆，要爆料给某个YouTuber看。哦？这涉及YouTube内部 drama？
that sounds like something from the previous story. So dishing the dirt, giving negative
就是那个视频创作者的负面新闻。确实是个爆料事件。
news on somebody else, spreading bad things about what somebody else did to other people.
这需要简单解释下，"爆料"这个词其实和前面故事有呼应——就是公开他人隐私、传播负面信息。
Yeah. So dirt in this case would be like bad information, negative,
是的。这里的"负面消息"可以理解为不良信息或负面内容，对吧？
something negative about someone and dishing it would be like serving it,
散布就是像端盘子一样，把东西摆出来
like putting it out there as if you're putting it on a dish and then serving it
就像把东西摆上盘子然后端出去一样
to people. So basically telling the world something bad about someone.
基本上就是公开传播关于某人的负面信息
Yes. YouTube drama. Okay.
对，就是YouTube那些乱七八糟的爆料
Yeah. But the room 101 is instant coffee. Instant coffee.
嗯，101房间是速溶咖啡
Oh yeah. Instant coffee. Instant coffee.
对，速溶咖啡
Right. So what is instant coffee? I mean,
对，那什么是速溶咖啡呢？
I guess everyone knows, but go ahead and give us an explainer.
每个人都知道，但请允许我们做个科普
Yeah, it could not be everywhere. I'd love it to not be everywhere and I will move there.
我希望它从 everywhere都不存在
Instant coffee is just granules, dry granules of, I would guess,
速溶咖啡其实就是磨碎的咖啡豆颗粒
processed coffee beans that you simply pick up a spoonful of, put them in your mug and
你只需舀一勺放进马克杯
then you put hot water on it and it supposedly creates a cup of coffee. But I disagree strongly.
倒上热水就能 supposed 冲泡出咖啡
Okay. Right. Would you like to lay out your case against instant coffee
好的，现在轮到你来反驳速溶咖啡
then? And also I guess dish the dirt on someone in the process.
顺便说说关于散布谣言的看法
Yeah. So I'm just, I know not everyone's into coffee and I am a coffee snob and I've spent a
我虽然不喝咖啡但我作为东道主
lot of money, too much money on a very nice coffee machine that will give me good espresso. But even
觉得应该提供比速溶咖啡更好的选择
if you're not into it, I feel like as a host, you should have something better than instant coffee.
具体是什么还没想好，可能得你们决定
I don't know what that is yet. It's for them to decide perhaps. But I just think we're,
但总觉得现在已经是2026年了
you know, it's 2025, 26 now - can't be making instant coffee.
居然还在用速溶咖啡
It's just, it's not, it's,
这已经过时了
it's not the done thing anymore. We're beyond that. We're better than that.
我们早该超越这个阶段
There's no excuse for instant coffee anymore. Is that what you're saying?
现在居然还有速溶咖啡的存在？
You're talking specifically as, as a guest in someone's home, when someone invites you in,
你是指作为客人到别人家做客时
they need to have something more to offer than just “Would you like a cup of coffee?
主人不该只提供"要不要喝咖啡"这样的选项？
It's instant. I hope that's all right.” As they pour it, as they prepare it for you.
这东西立即可用。我希望这样没问题。"他们倒咖啡时，为你准备咖啡时。
So you, yeah. Yeah. That's the thing because coffee can be so varied.
所以你，没错。没错。因为咖啡千变万化。
If you say, can I, do you want some coffee? And they don't say it's just instant. Then
如果你问"要喝咖啡吗"，对方不直接说"是速溶的"，
you're like, uh, well I need to judge whether I think you're a coffee snob to be able to say
你就会犹豫要不要判断对方是不是咖啡品鉴者，才能决定该不该答应。
yes or no to that question. Do you know what I mean? Because I I'm a, I'm quite sensitive
你明白吗？因为我特别敏感咖啡因，一天最多喝一两次。
to caffeine. I can't really have too many more, too many cups a day, one or two. So if they're,
所以如果他们给我咖啡，我希望是好的，否则就只喝水。
if they're offering me a coffee, I want it to be good. Otherwise I'll just have water.
是的。如果他们说"要喝杯咖啡吗"？
Yeah. So if they say, do you want a cup of coffee?
然后给我速溶咖啡，我不得不喝。
And then they give me a cup of instant. I've got to drink that.
但那太难喝了。因为你知道我一天已经有两杯咖啡了。
And it's just disgusting. Because you're thinking I've got two coffees
我不会浪费好咖啡杯来喝这种劣质货。
in me every day. I'm not going to waste one of those cups on this shit.
对，我要喝精致咖啡。但也让我陷入困境——
Yeah, exactly. You want the gourmet stuff. But it also puts me in a predicament where
在社交场合，他们喝茶或喝其他饮料，
I have to drink this because we're in a social setting,
我只能客套说"谢谢"，却不能直说"不用了"。
you know, they're drinking their cup of tea or whatever they're having.
更不能说"其实不用了，请倒掉吧"。
And I'm like, “Oh, thank you.” Cause you can't exactly . “Here you go.
因为对方刚泡好，你可以说"那倒掉算了"——
Here's your coffee.” “Oh, uh, actually on second thoughts. Uh, no. And I'll just leave it there
"虽然刚泡好，但既然我不喝，不如直接倒掉"。
actually. In fact, could you just pour it away? I know you've just made it, but you might as well
"我不喝，因为不知道是速溶的，我以为你用的是更好的"。
just pour that down the sink. Cause I'm not going to eat. I'm not going to drink
"不行，绝对不能这么做"。
that. I didn't know it was instant. I thought better. I thought you were better than that.”
我因此对Lucy降低了期待。那天去她家，
Yeah. You can't do that. No.
这是第二次见面，之前其实见过但不太熟。
And I thought better of this person. And this was, so when I went to their house,
Lucy问我要不要喝咖啡。天啊Lucy！
met them for the first, no, I had seen them before, but it was Lucy and Will.
Lucy，英式咖啡Lucy，Lucy！
So Lucy asked me, do you want a cup of coffee? Oh Lucy, Lucy, English with Lucy, Lucy,
天哪她居然给我速溶咖啡！我完全没想到！
Lucy. Yeah. Oh really. She, she gave you instant coffee. Yeah, no, that, I mean, I, I had higher
Lucy平时挺会待客的，怎么会用速溶？
expectations for Lucy. I didn't think she would be the kind of, “Oh, it's instant coffee.” Really?
因为对方刚泡好，你可以说"那倒掉算了"——
But I don't think she even said it's instant. And you know, she took me,
但我认为她甚至没有说是速溶咖啡。而且你知道的，她带我去，
I went via hers to go to where my wife live,
我经过她家去了我妻子住的地方，
uh, parent, her parents live. And it's through the Cotswolds and she had a lovely house.
呃，她父母住的地方。我们需要穿过科茨沃尔德地区，她家是个很不错的房子。
Very nice, very impressive. Went in and you know, yeah. For all of those reasons,
很漂亮，很让人印象深刻。一进去，你知道的，嗯。就因为那些原因，
I was like, surely she's got a good coffee set up.
我心想她肯定有套好咖啡设备吧。
Because you know, she's kind of in the middle of nowhere. She's not got a coffee shop around
因为毕竟她住在荒郊野岭的。她家门口没个咖啡店能买好咖啡，
the corner that she can go get a good coffee from. So you probably have your own setup.
所以你肯定自己准备了咖啡设备。
Um, but yeah, she gave me instant coffee. If she does ever watch this,
呃，不过她给了我速溶咖啡。如果她真看到这段视频，
I think she can handle this feedback. I think, I think she's bigger than this.
我想她能接受这个反馈。我觉得她不会这么敏感吧。
So that's fine. I think she can probably handle it. I mean, you know, uh, I guess so.
所以没关系。我觉得她能处理得了。你说是吧？
I mean, I don't think she's that, she's that,
我的意思是，她应该不算是，
uh, sensitive. Um, I think it's all right. I don't know.
呃，太敏感的人吧。我觉得问题不大。反正。
Do you think, do you really believe that Lucy Earl from English with Lucy
你觉得，你确定英式英语的Lucy Earle（来自《英语》栏目）不会比这更好的咖啡设备吗？
doesn't have a better coffee set up than that? Is there a chance,
Charlie？我得坦白说。有这种可能吗？
Charlie? And I'm sorry to say this. Is there a chance that she was like, just not, she was like,
Charlie？有可能她心想，
“Oh, there's the good coffee, but I'm not going to give it to Charlie.” Is that a possibility? Yeah.
"这里有好的咖啡，但我不给Charlie。"有可能吗？嗯。
Like the good China “don't get a good China out. It's just Charlie Baxter.
就像好茶具“别拿好茶具出来。给Charlie的就用速溶的。"
Give him the instant. Yeah. We've got Nescafe. Just give him that. Yeah.”
Yeah，我们有Nescafe。直接给他速溶的。嗯。
Is there a chance? It's like, I'm not going to use my, my, my gourmet stuff. Cause the shop is
有这种可能吗？就像我不使用我的精品咖啡豆，
20 minutes drive away and we've almost got none left. So give it, you just give him the instant.
因为我们开车去商店要20分钟，而且快没货了。那就给他速溶的。
It would be funny also if she only had a certain amount left and she poured,
如果她只剩这点咖啡了，自己冲了浓缩，给我倒速溶的，
she made herself an espresso and then she gave me instant like cheers. Yeah.
像干杯一样，那太尴尬了。呃。天哪。嗯。
That would be terrible. Um, wow. Yeah.
真没想到。她不是咖啡迷吗？你了解这种情况吗？
I am surprised. Well, is she not a coffee? Is she not a coffee person? Do you know about this?
难道不是茶党吗？我，我，我祈祷她不是咖啡爱好者。
Or is she more of a tea drinker or something? I, I, I pray that she's not a coffee drinker.
你觉得，你确定英式英语的Lucy Earle（来自《英语》栏目）不会比这更好的咖啡设备吗？
Uh, I, I think she's said, “Oh, we're not really a coffee, um, drinking household.”
呃，我想她说过："我们家的确不是个以喝咖啡为主的家庭。"
Uh, so yeah, for that reason, I kind of understand it, but still hosting,
所以我理解这个情况，但作为东道主...
I feel like I need a certain amount of teas available and I'm not a tea drinker,
我总觉得得备点茶水，虽然我本人不喝茶...
a certain amount of like, we don't have fizzy drinks necessarily, but if I know that we're
至少要有些碳酸饮料，但若知道要招待孩子...
hosting children, I'll probably get some in because they'll want that. Um, so yeah.
我可能会准备一些，毕竟孩子们会喜欢这个。
So you essentially suggesting that as a host of a person who's going to come around,
你 essentially 这是在说作为东道主...
you have a basic duty of care for that person, uh, which includes providing tea and coffee
就有基本照看义务，包括提供茶咖啡...
making facilities above the level of a, of a Premier Travel Inn, you know? But I I've seen
设施要优于 Premier 旅店的标准，你懂的？
in, uh, I've seen in Premier Inns, they now have these sachets that are more gourmet than Nescafe.
不过我在 Premier 旅馆见过更好的...
Okay. So just get those in. They’re like these, you know, longer sticks. And it's
现在用的这些茶包比雀巢更精致。
like a combination of milk and it's kind of instant, but it's, you know, a bit better.
是像这种长条包装的，混合了牛奶...
So that would be okay. Yeah. I mean, I'm not expecting them to buy a Nespresso machine.
速溶的但比普通速溶好些。
That's above and beyond. That's, that's too far. Where are you on the coffee sort of snobbery?
我可不会要求他们买意式咖啡机。
I don't know how to break this to you, Charlie. Oh no. Are you an instant man? Look at what I've
那就太离谱了。你属于咖啡偏见严重派吧？
got in my, in my, in my podcast room. I have a box of instant coffee sachets.
查理，你该不会是速溶派吧？看看我这播客房...
No. Yeah. But they're sachets.
我有整箱速溶咖啡包。
That's what I was talking about. They're not…
不，就是那种茶包。
It’s the same stuff. It's exactly the same stuff on the inside.
就是说的这个，里面东西完全一样。
This is in fact worse because I also throw away the sachets, you know, the, the,
但问题在于...更糟糕的是...
the empty sachets when I'm done. So it's exactly the same stuff on the inside, but it's just even
用完的包袋我还会特意丢掉，导致...
worse because there's more waste. Um, and then at home, at home we have a Nespresso machine,
所以里面东西一样，但浪费更严重。
which is, I think like in terms of quality, it's obviously a step up from, from instant coffee.
我们家确实有 Nespresso 咖啡机...
Um, but it's not, it's still not proper gourmet coffee, is it? I mean, we also have the, the,
质量确实比速溶好，但算真正的精品咖啡吗？
how do you call it? The cafetiere, which in America they call a French press. Yes.
我们那个叫法压壶的，美国叫 French press。
We have one of them, but just generally find that the results are never very good from the,
确实有台，但使用效果总不太理想...
from the cafetiere, the French press coffee maker.
从法压壶到法国手冲咖啡机。
And we have, you know, uh, would you call it coffee grains? Is that the right word? Ground
我们这里有，你知道的， uh，您说是咖啡豆吗？这个词准确吗？磨咖啡豆。
coffee, ground coffee. That's what I mean. You can see that I'm more of a tea drinker.
就是磨咖啡豆。这就是我说的意思。您可以看出我更喜欢喝茶。
So, and so it just don't, we don't get very good results from that at home. For some reason,
所以，而且我们家用那个效果不太好。不知道为什么，
we just haven't found the right coffee and the Nespresso machine is very expensive to
我们还没找到合适的咖啡，而且奈斯普索咖啡机很贵，
buy the capsules. And you know, we have busy lives. And so we do have a jar of Nescafe,
买胶囊也不便宜。毕竟生活很忙，所以我们家也有，
whatever it is, special, special, whatever. Can't remember the actual name of the stuff,
一罐 Nescafe，不管什么特殊什么特殊，记不清具体名字了，
but yeah, we do, we do drink instant coffee at home as well Charlie, I'm sorry.
I'm really, really sad to hear that. I think you've just reminded me that
听到您这样我很失望。我想这或许适合您的情况，
a good option for maybe your situation, or if you don't have a coffee enthusiasm,
或者如果您对咖啡 нет энтузиазма（俄语非热情），
if you're not enthusiastic about coffee and you still want to host and have better than Nescafe,
但还想举办聚会又不想喝低于 Nescafe 的品质，
just get a mocha pot, like an Italian percolator, you know, those hexagon hexagon shaped kind of
就买摩卡壶，比如意大利虹吸壶，知道那种六边形六边形造型的锅吗？
pots that you twist like that. Pop them on a stove and that percolates, I think the coffee through,
你像这样转着用。放在炉子上煮，让水通过咖啡，
or the water goes through the coffee and it's lovely. I used to have one of them.
买胶囊也不便宜。毕竟生活很忙，所以我们家也有，
I used to have one of them. I don't know what happened to it. Why did I stop using that? I think
一罐 Nescafe，不管什么特殊什么特殊，记不清具体名字了，
maybe I kind of melted it or something. One day I forgot, I left it on the stove and forgot. And
8, 但确实，确实在家也喝速溶咖啡，Charlie，实在抱歉。
like the handle melted off or something, something terrible happened. I nearly burnt the house down.
听到您这样我很失望。我想这或许适合您的情况，
That's a good option. That's like 10 quid and it will,
或者如果您对咖啡 нет энтузиазма（俄语非热情），
unless you burn it like you did, it will last a long time. Yeah. Hmm.
好的。那我接受101房间喝速溶咖啡吗？嗯，
Okay. So do I accept instant coffee in room 101? Well,
我真的很失望，实在抱歉打断。就是觉得，
I'm so sad that, sorry to interrupt. I'm just so sad and disappointed that you drink.
你居然喝这个？是吗？不。我喝的是水。
Is that, is that instant right there? No. So this is, this is, I'm drinking,
14, 或咖啡通过水，味道很棒。我以前有个这样的。
this is water. Have you heard of it? I don't know if you've ever,
15, 我以前有个这样的。不知道怎么弄丢的。怎么不用了？可能熔化了？
um, no, I don't know what it is because it's not transparent.
16, 有天忘关炉子，把把手烧变形了。差点烧着房子。
That cup is not transparent. I'm drinking,
因为不透明。
listeners, I'm drinking from a sort of a paper cup.
听众朋友们，我正用一种纸杯喝水。
Um, I'm drinking water from a paper cup. And so Charlie,
嗯，我用水喝的纸杯。所以查理，
yeah. Also you can't see through it because it's not transparent.
对吧？而且你看不透因为它不透明。
Um, this is, I mean, your life is, it's a nightmare, isn't it? Not being able to see
嗯，这就像...你的生活，仿佛被困在迷雾中，不是吗？无法看透事物本质。
through things. Is that, you'd like to live in a world where everything was transparent. You
难道你想生活在一切透明化的世界里？那样你就能直接看透一切。
can just see straight through everything. So then you know where you are, you know, what's going on.
即使进入露西家门前就能看清状况。
You can see even before you enter Lucy's house,
没问题。因为所有东西都是玻璃做的，能直接看到厨房。
it's all right. Cause everything's made of glass. So you can actually see into
所以能提前准备，知道这里只有速溶咖啡。
the kitchen and you can prepare yourself for the fact that it’s instant coffee.
因为你能预判到，你渴望透明世界。
Because you can see in advance, you know, that you want to live in a kind
我是在温室里长大的，可能因此...嗯，是的。
of see-through world. I was raised in a, in a greenhouse. So maybe that is why, but yes, yes.
我确实向往。是的。
I'd love that. Right. Right.
好的。抱歉...我确实有点让你失望。
Okay. Well, I'm sorry to, yeah, I'm sorry to disappoint you by the way. So this,
这杯我用来喝水的杯子，其实早上是从面包店买的咖啡壶装满的。
this cup that I'm drinking the water from, I actually,
所以每天我来这里会先买杯咖啡。
this was filled with coffee from a boulangerie this morning.
通常路上买现磨咖啡，但喝完水后再用水杯续杯。
So when I come here in the mornings,
所以这里虽然有速溶咖啡，但我很少用。
normally I will grab a coffee on the way and then sort of like have it here. And then I,
我更习惯外带现磨咖啡。
I use the cup to drink my water from, uh, while I'm in, in my room. So yeah.
但这样确实方便多了，能喝到真正的咖啡。
So I have instant coffee here, but I don't,
那位咖啡师真是天降甘霖，但你居然能接受速溶咖啡...
I don't actually use it very much. I tend to just get coffees from outside. Okay.
对比太强烈了。不过可以理解。
But that's, that's quite, that's a lot better. Yes. You're getting the real stuff.
在办公室这点我得辩护：这间没洗手池。
A barista is giving you a godsend of a gift, but I'm just surprised that you're then able
虽然走廊有，但谁会去麻烦呢，
to palette instant coffee in comparison. Like the contrast is just so different.
所以每天我来这里会先买杯咖啡。
In my defence here in my office, I don't have, um, I don't have a sink in this room.
通常路上买现磨咖啡，但喝完水后再用水杯续杯。
There is one down the corridor, but it's down the corridor. Who can be bothered to,
所以这里虽然有速溶咖啡，但我很少用。
to, to walk, uh, get some, put something on my feet and walk down a corridor and unlock
要走到走廊，嗯，穿上鞋子，然后去解锁
a door. I mean, it's so inconvenient. So I just tend to, you know, the, the,
一扇门。我的意思是，这太不方便了。我通常就直接——
I would have my own coffee making machine here and stuff, but I'd have to clean it.
要是我这里有现成的咖啡机就好了，但得收拾清洗
And then I’d have to deal with the waste of the, uh, the, the coffee, uh, granules,
还要处理咖啡粉渣这些垃圾，
uh, the ground coffee, you know, and it's just like a lot of faff. And so, uh, instant coffee,
嗯，磨碎的咖啡豆什么的，总之很麻烦。所以速溶咖啡的便利性实在让人无法抗拒
just, just the sheer convenience of it wins. It's, it's convenient.
简直是无可替代。确实很方便。
I'll give you that. But, um, so, okay. Are there other problems
我承认。但还有其他问题吗？
that you have with it? What exactly is the nature of your issue with it? Is
你具体是哪里不满意？是味道不好？
it that it tastes bad? Is it that it's, it's unhealthy? What is it?
还是健康问题？到底什么问题？
It's the flavour profile. Yeah. It's just disgusting. It smells like a teacher's breath.
是风味不对。真让人作呕。闻起来像老教师的口气。
It's, it's just awful. Um, and, and yeah, it's poor quality. I imagine it's terrible for you.
真是糟糕透顶。而且质量太差。
I don't know. I haven't looked into that,
我没仔细研究过，但估计也糟糕。
but I imagine it is. I think I genuinely want Nescafe to burn to the ground.
我真希望Nescafe品牌彻底毁灭。
I think that brand itself, I hate.
我讨厌这个牌子。
Why?
为什么？
Because they are the instant coffee. Aren't they? They, they pioneered it. I think
因为他们是速溶咖啡的鼻祖啊？
That's their business. They certainly got ahold of it and they made it theirs.
这本来就是他们的业务。他们确实掌控了市场。
Yeah. I think I want the whole of Nescafe in room 101. So you're
我倒想整个Nescafe品牌都进101号房间。
throwing the entire company in as well. All those jobs, all those job losses, Charlie.
你这是要把整家企业都扔进去啊，查理。那些工作机会呢？
But they can go and learn how to make real coffee and,
让他们去学怎么煮真正的好咖啡，
and share it with the world. Because it's such a lovely thing.
然后和全世界分享这美好的事物。
They won't have to be able to afford to do it because they won't have a job,
反正他们以后也没工作，用不着花钱
but you know, at least, um, yes.
但至少——
Okay. Instant coffee. Is it going in? Well, I'm sorry. It's not going to happen,
速溶咖啡？要进黑名单？不，绝对不行。
Charlie. I'm sorry. I get your point. I do understand. I appreciate your
查理，我明白你的观点。我确实在认真考虑。
argument. I appreciate your commitment to quality coffee.
论点。我欣赏你对高品质咖啡的坚持。
What about, you know, maybe it's not gone forever, but what about the hosting
再想想看，或许它还没完全消失，但关于待客之道——拥有更好的待客之道，你觉得呢？对吧。所以具体来说，
situation of having something better than that to offer? Right. So the specifically,
将要提供的东西，并不是仅仅给速溶咖啡。
the thing that's going to go in is, is not offering more than just instant coffee.
嗯，当邀请客人时，这确实很难融入。我们会想办法。
Um, when you invite someone, right. That's quite a complicated one to stick in. We'll find a way.
去主动获取更好的东西，露西，你听到没？如果你在听，你听到没？他对咖啡不满意，你听到没？好吧。
It's, it's the decency to go out and get something better. Did you hear that Lucy? If you're
我明白。我很容易被说服，查理。我真是震惊到了。
listening, did you hear that? He wasn't happy about the coffee. Did you get that? Oh, um, okay.
我觉得这次要插一杠子了。你待客时会考虑客人吗？会主动提供饮品，还是认为他们能自取？就像有人要来家里做客——天啊。
I see. I'm very easily persuaded, Charlie. I'm very, I'm a pushover.
他们什么时候走？给他们这个，或许就会走。呃，不，我觉得不止如此。呃，通常我们会拿出胶囊咖啡机，
I feel like I'm going to put this one in. I'd like to know what you are like when you host, do
把尘封的机器重新启用，提供 Nespresso 咖啡。
you think about who you're hosting? Do you think about getting anything in or do you think, ah,
如果来家里维修的工匠，我会递 Nespresso。好吧。如果来客人，
they can fend for themselves generally? Just like, Oh God, some people are coming over. Oh dear.
当然会提供。Nespresso 和一系列茶饮，
When are they going to leave? Just give them this and maybe then they'll go, go away. Um, no, I
不同种类的茶饮都会准备。嗯，没错，我同意。
don't think that I don't think that's all. Um, no, normally we would, we would offer the Nespresso as
我的意思是，基本同意在待客时提供速溶咖啡是吧？对。
the, we'd like dust off the Nespresso machine and get that up and running and offer that.
你作为东道主可以做得更好。我真是震惊到了。
Um, if a tradesman comes round, I'll offer them a Nespresso. Okay. If we,
我真的受惊了。希望露西在《露西的居家管理》能看到这段。我说正经的，
if we have people round, sure.
她有八百多万订阅者，居然连杯咖啡都搞不定。显然她把所有时间都花在拍视频上，
It's Nespresso and a range, a range of teas,
而不是考虑咖啡相关事宜，查理。
different types of tea options are provided too. Um, yeah, yeah, yeah. I agree.
我明白。我很容易被说服，查理。我真是震惊到了。
I mean, I, I agree basically that I think in, uh, offering instant coffee is it? Yeah.
我觉得这次要插一杠子了。你待客时会考虑客人吗？会主动提供饮品，还是认为他们能自取？就像有人要来家里做客——天啊。
You could do better definitely as a host. And I'm, I'm, I'm shocked.
他们什么时候走？给他们这个，或许就会走。呃，不，我觉得不止如此。呃，通常我们会拿出胶囊咖啡机，
I'm genuinely shocked. Uh, I hope Lucy watches this at Lucy's housekeeping. I mean,
把尘封的机器重新启用，提供 Nespresso 咖啡。
seriously, I expected so much more from her.
如果来家里维修的工匠，我会递 Nespresso。好吧。如果来客人，
Clearly her priorities are towards making YouTube videos. I mean, 8.7 something,
当然会提供。Nespresso 和一系列茶饮，
19 million subscribers, and she can't get any. Clearly she spends all her time
不同种类的茶饮都会准备。嗯，没错，我同意。
dealing with YouTube and not enough time thinking about coffee, Charlie.
我的意思是，基本同意在待客时提供速溶咖啡是吧？对。
Yeah, clearly. Yeah. Okay.
嗯，当然。好吧。
In that case, that's going to go into room 101 then basically English with Lucy, not,
那样的话，基本就归到101号房了——和Lucy的英语区，不过
not providing proper coffee making facilities. That's what's going to go into room 101. Uh, here.
没提供正常的咖啡制作设施。这就是101号房的内容。
Okay. I'm pulling the lever. There it goes.
好的。我拉了拉杠杆。好了。
That's a message. That's a message. We sent a message to English with Lucy.
这是条消息。我们给Lucy的英语区发了条消息。
Get your coffee situation sorted. Sort it out, Lucy. Sort it out.
你先把咖啡事解决好。Lucy，赶紧处理！
And this is a, an indication to the audience of how indirect our culture is. You know,
这也说明了我们文化的间接性。各位知道吧，
this is years of this brewing and, uh, and I've not been able to say it to, I
这种隔阂已经积累多年，但我当时没敢说出口。当时我只会说
obviously didn't say anything in the moment. I was like, Oh, this is lovely.
这多可爱啊。多可爱。
Lovely. Yeah. Hmm.
嗯。你好吗？呃，
Yeah. How are you? Um, and, and it's taken this video to be able
现在通过这条视频，才有勇气背后捅她一刀说这些，希望视频能传到她那里。
to have the guts to backstab her in the back and say this and hope that somehow
这就是英国人处理冲突的方式吧。
this video gets to her. So that's how Brits deal with confrontation.
是不是特别阴险？确实。这就是英国文化的缩影。
Yeah. It's very sort of underhanded, isn't it? Yeah. Well, what an indictment of British culture.
难道我是异类？英国人真的会这么做吗？还是说我太刻薄了像个母老虎？
Maybe I'm the odd one out. Would you say that Brits do do that? Or I'm a
我的理解是——呃，我不确定。如果受邀去别人家喝速溶咖啡，
bit savage and I'm a bit of a bitch. Uh, I dunno.
谁会转身就骂"这咖啡他妈的差劲"？
I think that, I think that probably, uh, I don't think, I don't know if anyone would,
出了什么问题？你们不提供正常咖啡啊？Lucy，说人话。
um, if invited to someone's house and given instant coffee,
父母的妈的！我觉得没人会这么做吧？有人吗？
I don't know if anyone would just turn around and say, fucking hell, this coffee's rubbish.
我觉得大多数人都会礼貌道谢，比如"谢谢咖啡"。
What's the matter with you? Could don't have normal, proper coffee. Come on, Lucy.
可能根本不会有人走得更远，比如说"哇，这 Nescafe gold blend 好好喝"。
Fuck's sake. I don't think anyone's gonna do that. Are they? Um, I think most,
我也不确定你当时有没有这么做。但普遍来说，
most people would probably be polite enough to sort of say, Oh, thanks a lot for the coffee.
即便有人觉得咖啡难喝，也不会当面对主人说三道四。
Well, they might not even might, they might not go the extra mile and say, Hmm, this
更不会像某些人那样，在视频里公开嘲讽。
is delicious. What is this? Nescafe gold blend. Ooh, I don't think they would do.
所以说，这种公开场合的羞辱确实罕见。
I don't, I don't think you did that either. Um, but I don't think anyone would, would
因此我猜测，你也没这么做吧？
instantly criticise the coffee if they'd been invited round. But would they years
如果当时被邀请到家里品尝咖啡的话，他们肯定当场就会批评这咖啡。但等几年后，他们会不会拍个YouTube视频来吐槽？啊，这可是你苦心经营了这么久的目的呢。
later then make a YouTube video about it? Oh, this is what you've been building up to this.
所以我得赶紧把YouTube的播放量搞上去，好让Lucy能间接收到我的信息。说真的，现在感觉像是一块大石头终于落地，轻松多了，确实有解压效果。
So I've got to get my, I've got to get my YouTube, um, uh, um, views up to get that
我们会等Lucy给出某种回应。直觉告诉我不会有任何回复，她根本不可能看到这条信息。
message back to Lucy in the most indirect way possible. But genuinely, I feel like a
但以防万一...好吧，我们期待她的回应。说不定这会掀起YouTube的巨浪，成为"咖啡门"事件。
weight has been lifted off my shoulders now feel a bit easier. Like, yeah, it's a bit therapeutic.
咖啡门？没错。
We'll wait for Lucy to respond in some way. I get the feeling there'll be zero,
对的。确实不错。
there'll be no response whatsoever. She will never see this.
我在几个WhatsApp群里都有她。她可能会把我踢出去。没错。
Uh, but just in case she does, then, you know, well, we look forward to seeing what
你会突然发现收不到那个群的推送了，然后翻遍WhatsApp和网页都找不到。天啊！
the response will be. And maybe this is going to be a huge, like storm on YouTube,
我被禁言了？她肯定有足够的人脉能在YouTube封了我的频道。是的。
a massive YouTube drama, the coffee, the coffee files. What would it be? Coffee gate.
到此为止了。
Oh, coffee gates. Okay. Yeah.
可悲。得走了。对了，现在雀巢咖啡破产了，你不如创立个速溶咖啡品牌？
Yeah. Yeah. It's good.
为什么不开速溶咖啡？不，但要是能做出高品质速溶呢？我觉得可行。
I'm on a few WhatsApp groups with her. Maybe she'll kick me off them. Yeah.
毕竟制作过程需要时间，就像给咖啡杯加料。
You'll suddenly find that you're not getting notifications from that group
爱乐压壶也是选项。我常用它露营。
and you'll search your WhatsApp and web. It's not here. Oh no.
它有特定...帐篷显然更适合露营。
I've been, I've been cancelled. She probably knows enough people in YouTube to ban my channel. Yeah.
翻译结果：
Yeah. That's it. It's over for you now.
我在几个WhatsApp群里都有她。她可能会把我踢出去。没错。
Oh dear. Better go. And I don't know, since Nescafe's been, been, um, bankrupted, maybe
你会突然发现收不到那个群的推送了，然后翻遍WhatsApp和网页都找不到。天啊！
you can set up some sort of coffee company making convenient coffee, instant coffee.
我被禁言了？她肯定有足够的人脉能在YouTube封了我的频道。是的。
Why don't you set up an instant coffee? Nah, but good quality, good quality, instant. I
到此为止了。
think it's possible to make good quality instant coffee. I mean, it should be instant process.
可悲。得走了。对了，现在雀巢咖啡破产了，你不如创立个速溶咖啡品牌？
Does that not ruin the quality? I don't know. I'm no expert. No,
为什么不开速溶咖啡？不，但要是能做出高品质速溶呢？我觉得可行。
it does take a little bit of time to, to give some love into the cup of coffee.
毕竟制作过程需要时间，就像给咖啡杯加料。
Aeropress is another one. I use that for camping and Aeropress.
爱乐压壶也是选项。我常用它露营。
It's a specific... Surely a tent would be a better idea for camping.
它有特定...帐篷显然更适合露营。
Haha. Aeropress. What's that? It's like a cylinder, uh, pressure,
嘿嘿。爱乐压？那是什么？像个圆筒，呃，用压力？
a bit like a cafetiere, but it's like this very unique brand that have done so well that like,
类似法压壶，但这是一个非常独特的品牌，他们做得很好，所以
there's a real like cult around them that there's annual competition of,
就围绕他们形成了一个小圈子，甚至有年度比赛
of people making the best coffee they can possibly make with an Aeropress.
让人们用爱乐压制作最佳咖啡
Yeah. It's quite cheap as well. It's not too much money, but I mean, it's just plastic.
而且价格也不贵，不算太贵，但材质就是塑料
So it's a cylinder. Yeah. It's two cylinders that like push together and then, yeah.
就是两个圆筒，你把它们推合在一起
Outcomes. Good coffee happens. Good coffee happens.
结果就出来了，好咖啡就出来了
Exactly. Yeah. Okay.
对吧？没错
All right. Well there we, Lucy, you've heard all the different options. There's Nespresso.
好吧，露西，你已经了解所有选项了：雀巢胶囊咖啡机、爱乐压、法压壶
There's, there's Aeropress. There's the cafetiere. There's the Italian thing that I melted.
还有那个我熔化的意大利玩意儿
You know, there's lots of different options, Lucy. So pick one and just sort it out. Right.
你知道有很多选择，露西，选一个搞定就行
Let's move on then to your third and final, uh, thing that you would, you,
那接下来进入你第三且最后，呃，想放进101房间的东
you think should go into room 101, Charlie. Okay. So this is a bit weird.
西，查理。有点奇怪
I understand you might ban it, but I want to try it. Um, so when I go into a restaurant,
我明白你会禁止它，但我还是想试试。每次去餐厅
I sit down, look at a menu and, um, I read the menu, especially this is stupid because we're
坐下看菜单，读菜单，嗯，因为我们教英语
teaching English, which teaching languages, we should be able to do this, but should be
教语言应该能看懂，但确实应该能看懂
able to read, should be able to read. But for some reason, firstly, I don't know how to read a menu.
但奇怪的是，首先我就不会看菜单
Like I just, I just look over it. And I, and then I,
我只是快速扫一眼，同时还要社交
cause I'm also socialising. Normally it's like, I haven't seen that person in a while.
通常是和很久没见的人见面
So I'm like juggling the socialising and I'm looking down and the waiter comes over and he's
所以我要同时社交和看菜单，服务员过来问我要什么
like, what would you like? I'm like, I don't know. And I look back and, and it's just, it's
我就说不知道，然后看回菜单纸上那些奇怪图案
just these weird shapes on the paper. I do look, I do feel like I've got dyslexia for a food menu.
我确实会觉得自己对食物菜单有阅读障碍
But also beyond that, if I do actually spend the time of like, okay, the title of the food is this,
更别提点餐时，比如这道菜的名称是...
and this is the ingredients, nothing happens for me. There's no emotion or there's no
这种材料是...
like connection with what I'm actually going to eat. I feel like any pictures.
但这对我来说毫无意义，既没有情感共鸣
I mean, I don't want to be that person,
我的意思是，我不想成为那样的人，
but I also do. I love pictures menu. He's just, he can't read menus.
但我又忍不住。我喜欢图片菜单。他只是，他看不懂菜单。
He can't, he can't read. Do you have anything? Yeah. But my argument here is, you know,
他看不懂，真的看不懂。你有其他办法吗？有。但我的观点是，你知道的，
we're, we're buying something that is so far from language.
我们购买的东西离语言越远。
We're wanting a sensory input of food. You know,
我们想要的只是对食物的感官体验。你知道的，
why are we, why are we dealing with words? Words is so that we can do
为什么非要的文字？文字是为了让我们做得更好。
better than that. You mean we need a whole new paradigm of communication for menus.
难道我们需要为菜单建立全新的沟通范式？
So just simply like you're saying words, language, written language is not enough
就像你说的，文字、书面语言根本不足以
to somehow capture the experience of eating the food. You're thinking this,
某种程度还原用餐体验。你也是这么想的，
these words, it's just not enough. Can you actually maybe directly, can you,
这些文字，真的不够。能让我先品尝食物，再通过其他感官体验吗？
can I taste the food first and just add more senses? I want to see it.
我要看它。我要尝它。我要摸它。
I want to taste it. I want to feel it, touch it here.
就像我们去冰淇淋店时，不都能看到冰淇淋吗？
In my defence, what do we do when we go to an ice cream parlour? Yeah, we can see the ice cream.
你说得对，还能试吃。领个小勺子。
You've got a good point. And taste it. You get a couple of tasters.
但查理，这会彻底摧毁餐厅行业。如果每位顾客
But Charlie, this is going to completely ruin the restaurant business. If every customer who
进门就要试吃每道菜，亲眼看看。
comes in wants to taste every item on the menu and see it. No, I'm not saying that.
不，我并不是这个意思。
The whole, the whole restaurant system will,
整个餐饮体系，
will just be brought to its knees by this change. If it's just not practical. No,
只会被这种变革压垮。如果不可行。
I don't expect that, but I'm making the point that words don't do enough.
我不期待这样，但我想强调文字不够。
I think photos, if they're done in a, in a tasteful artistic way,
如果用精心设计的艺术化摄影，
I think that would be the way to go. But I just, I also don't like a QR code cause
我觉得这才是可行方案。只是，
then we're on our devices as soon as we sit down. So I don't know the solution.
我也不喜欢二维码，一坐下就要掏手机。
I'd like to find one together potentially. So you're suggesting that we get rid of traditional
所以我不知该如何解决。或许我们可以共同探索。
menus with words and you replace it with just, I don't know, just something better, please. Yeah.
你建议我们摒弃传统文字菜单，换成什么？
The menu opens up says, I don't know. Something else. I don't know.
菜单打开后说是"其他选项"什么的，我就不知道了。
Uh, ask the waiter to try, you know, good luck. Yeah. Now the,
呃，你去问问服务员试试吧，你知道的，祝你好运。好的。现在，
the, the closest thing I am satisfied with is when there is a QR code additionally.
我能接受的最近的只有当有二维码作为补充时。
So I can open the menu, look at the words, feel like I don't know what they mean. And
我可以打开菜单，看那些字，感觉像是不认识它们的意思。然后
then later on, I look, I scan the QR code and get the photos. In your defence, Charlie, these days,
等后来我一看，扫了二维码就得到了图片。 Charlie，你辩解一下，
um, restaurant menus are often written with a lot of pretentious, uh, fancy language.
这些天餐厅菜单总是用很多矫饰的、华丽的辞藻。
Aren't they? I've heard that it's adjectives, add money to the dish. Like the more adjectives
是吗？我听说形容词能增加菜品价格，比如形容词越多，
they can put into it, the more money they can charge for the dish. Okay.
菜品价格就能定得越高。好吧。
Yes. I, that, that makes sense. So if, if it's basically, I don't know what,
对。就是，这样吧。比如，比如像牛排薯条，
like a steak and chips, it would be like a pan seared, uh, you know, rump of Angus beef,
可能会写成平底煎的安格斯牛柳，用黑胡椒酱 lovingly 酱腌，
um, lovingly marinated in pepper sauce with bloody, bloody, blah, blah, blah, blah.
血淋淋的等等之类的。
What you need is beef, steak, and chips. That's what you need.
你需要的是牛肉、牛排和薯条。这就是你需要的东西。
That was like, you were reading a menu.
就像在看菜单。
That was very good. Yeah, exactly that. Exactly that.
这倒是很到位。嗯，没错。没错。
Yeah. And they also remove, they remove the price apparently. And that helps
对。他们还会把价格去掉。这样能
improve sales because we don't concern ourselves.
提升销量，因为我们不会在意。
Oh no, it's not the price. It's the currency next to the number. They remove that apparently
哦不，不是价格本身，是货币单位。他们好像也去掉了那个，
psychologically that improves or deters us from going for the bigger one, the more expensive.
心理上这样会让我们更倾向或却步于高价选项。
Like, you know, pan seared beef rump with, um, I don't know what's a fancy word for chips. I don't
比如，你知道怎么用 fancy 词形容薯条吗？比如比利时薯条或...
know what that would be like Belgian fries or... Beer battered, double glazed something. Yeah.
啊，我不清楚那种词。嗯，可能是啤酒裹炸之类的。嗯。
Beer battered, double glazed, um, uh, potato fritters or something like that. It's like,
啤酒裹炸，双面煎什么的。类似这种。就是说，
you mean chips. Um, and then the number next to it,
你指的是薯条。嗯，然后旁边的数字，
let's say it's 37 cause it's quite a fancy restaurant.
假设说37，因为是一家挺高端的餐厅。
Yeah. And it's, if it said 37 pounds, he'd be like,
对。如果写成37英镑，
there's no way I'm going to buy that 37 pounds. But if, cause it says 37, you're like 37.
他绝对舍不得买这37英镑的。但要是没写货币单位，
Yeah, it's fine. Yeah. Yeah.
你就会觉得只是37，没问题。嗯，是的。好的。
Yeah. I've got 37. Yeah.
嗯。我有37了。嗯。
Yeah. No worries. 37.
嗯。没问题。37。
I can count to 37. It's not that high. Is it? Yeah.
我数到37没问题。就那么回事吧？嗯。
No worries. This one's just 37. No, no, it's 37 pounds.
没问题。这个就是37英镑。不不，就是37英镑。
37 pounds. Pounds. 37 pounds.
37英镑。英镑。37英镑。
But of course not. I'll go for the one that's 36. Which is, we are in the UK.
但当然不是。我要选36英镑的。我们是在英国。
We do deal with pound sterling. I thought it was just 37, like,
我们确实用英镑结算。我以为就是37，比如，
I don't know, 37, like it's a stone or something. I don't know.
我不知道，37可能像块石头什么的。我不知道。
37 pounds of this changes everything. Yeah. It does something apparently to our brains,
37英镑的量会改变一切。嗯。好像会影响大脑，
but yes, I, I, I don't have anything against adjectives.
但是的，我，我，我没什么反对形容词的。
I like the senses being stimulated,
我喜欢感官被调动起来，
but as an English teacher, I'm very happy to hear you say that Charlie Baxter quote,
但作为英语老师，我很高兴听到你说查理·巴斯特的话，
I have nothing against adjectives. British English podcasts. Great podcasts.
我没什么反对形容词的。英式英语播客。很好的播客。
Um, but yeah, I just, what do you feel about when you read a menu? Are
嗯，不过 yeah，当你读菜单时，你觉得怎样？你，
you fine about reading the menu? Are you normal? Well, you know, I live in France,
你觉得读菜单正常吗？正常吗？我住在法国，
so there's the whole other level of the fact is written in a whole different language,
我们确实用英镑结算。我以为就是37，比如，
Charlie. So I've got to understand the French as well. Oh God.
好的。那是什么？就是牛排薯条啊。嗯。
All right. Uh, what is that? It's just steak and chips. Yeah.
好的。我要那个。嗯，所以是牛排薯条，但不，在英国，
All right. I'll have that. Um, so there's that, but no, in England, no, of course I kind of,
我在一定程度上同意矫饰的观点，我同意你说的，
I agree with the pretentious, I agree with your point about how irritating it is that,
菜单不清晰地描述食物让人很烦，你明白吧？
uh, menus often don't really describe it in a clear way.
你会看到很多华丽辞藻却令人困惑，
Instead, you get a lot of fancy language that is a bit confusing and you can spend quite a lot of
你得花不少时间猜菜单到底写的什么。
time sitting there just trying to understand what it is you're going to get. So I agree with that,
所以我同意这点，菜单有明确目的，
that menus should be, they have a purpose, which is to tell you exactly what you're
就是告诉你到底吃什么。当它们，
going to get. And when they, um, confuse the matter with, um, too much descriptive language,
用过多的描述性语言混淆视听时，
cause they're trying to raise the price of the food and that's definitely irritating.
因为他们想提高食品价格，这确实让人不快。
So I agree with that, but I don't think we should throw the baby out with the
所以我同意这个观点，但我觉得不能因噎废食，完全取消纸质菜单。
bath water and just get rid of printed menus entirely. Um, I mean, you could raise your,
我的意思是，你可以适当提升词汇量，比如多使用形容词。
your, your vocab potentially maybe, you know, like embrace adjectives. Um, yeah, I'm sure
你，你的，你的词汇量应该能提升吧，比如可以尝试用形容词描述。
you're I think it is on me actually, because, uh, I sound very sexist here, but I don't cook.
可能问题在我身上，因为我听起来像个性别歧视者，但我确实不会做饭。
My wife cooks. She's been raised right by a chef. Her dad was a chef.
我妻子会做饭。她从小由主厨父亲培养长大。
Her whole family know how to cook really,
她整个家族都擅长烹饪，非常专业。
really well. I used to cook when I was at uni, but basic stuff. And then she took over.
我大学时也学做饭，但只是做些基础菜。后来她接手了。
We were like, Oh, I should probably keep it up for the first five years of our life. We
我们刚结婚头五年，每周让我做一餐，结果我花 forever 做顿基础餐。
did one meal a week where I did it. And I took forever to cook a basic meal.
她就说"查理，放弃吧"。所以我很久没正经做饭了。
And she was like, just give up Charlie. So I haven't cooked properly for a very
她生病时偶尔做点，但我的食材词汇量很匮乏。
long time. Occasionally when she's feeling sick, I'll do something.
对食物准备方法的理解也很差，只能吃的时候简单判断"好喝"或"难吃"。
But, um, so my food vocabulary is very poor. So it is probably something to do with that
这大概就是我处理菜单困难的原因。
and my understanding of how to prepare food. And I just eat it and think yum or think yuck.
我的食物智商就这水平，所以点菜单确实有困难。
And that's, that's my IQ with food. So that's probably why I struggle with a menu. Yeah.
Yeah.
Hmm. I'm not going to put a written menus into room 101. I might put pretentiously worded written
我不会把纸质菜单扔进房间101，但可能放些自命不凡的纸质菜单。
menus, um, into room 101, but your, I think your, uh, original statement was written menus.
你说的纸质菜单？我可能误解了。
Is that not right? I can't put that into room 101 because I'm not going to go into a restaurant
不，不能往餐厅菜单里放这种东西，因为我不愿去餐厅盲目点餐。
and just, um, and just try to, you know, just, just cross my fingers and hope for the best. I,
我必须看清菜单内容。
you know, I want to see what I'm going to get. Yeah, I do agree with that.
Yeah，我同意。
It's absolutely fair. Do you like photos? Would
你喜欢照片吗？
you like to see nicely taken photos? It sounds like a sales pitch. It's like,
你喜欢看精心拍摄的照片吗？
it was like, do you like photos? Well, yeah, of course he doesn't like photos.
听起来像推销话术，就像问"你喜欢照片吗？"
Right. It's like, well, do you like photo menu? Um, no, of course I like photos, but I don't know.
当然不喜欢，这明显是推销手段。
Why don't restaurants use photos more in their menus? Why is that? Is it because every time you
为什么餐厅不用更多照片在菜单上？
see a, a menu with photos on it, only certain kinds of kind of crap restaurants have photos.
看到带照片的菜单，只有某些低档餐厅才会用照片装饰菜单。
Don't they? Well, I think what happened was Brits went abroad.
难道不是吗？我认为问题出在以前英国人出国就餐时。
We couldn't understand their language. And then they figured out they don't,
我们看不懂他们的语言，后来发现他们发现菜单不标注价格。
they sell more if they slap a photo of the pizza on the menu in really obvious resort
他们发现只要在明显显眼的度假村菜单上放披萨照片，销量就会增加。
kind of restaurants that are just focused on the location and not about the food.
这类只注重地理位置而非食物本身的餐厅。
And I think that kind of plastic laminated album of menu with loads of photos somehow
这种装帧精美的带海量照片的菜单手册
made the whole industry look at it and think, no, we're not doing that. So I
促使整个行业意识到不应该这样做，因此
think it's got a bad name for it, but since COVID, I think some of the QR codes have
它给行业留下了负面印象，但自从疫情以来
created some really nice options of apps and like good photography of food. Yeah.
二维码催生了应用程序和优质菜品摄影的良性发展。
Okay. You may have a point there, but there's a,
你或许有道理，但市场上确实存在
there's a, there's a sort of a gap in the market for the, uh, a more high quality,
更高质量高端餐饮带照片的菜单
high end menu with photos on it. Um, so yeah, that's another thing for you to innovate, Charlie,
这类产品存在市场空缺
as well as like decent quality instant coffee, you could go for a high, high class photo menu.
因此除了提供合格速溶咖啡，你们还可以创新推出
I mean, I was in a cafe yesterday and, uh,
一款配备高品质菜品摄影的高端菜单
I had a double screen up and my friend told me that I should never do that again. He was like,
我昨天在咖啡馆的经历是
that is so geeky. I've got like a, like a, a monitor above my laptop.
我用了双屏显示器，朋友劝我别再这么操作
It's like a portable one. And I thought, Oh, I'm geeky. Yeah.
他说这太技术宅了，他电脑上还装着
I'm enjoying myself here. And then I looked to my right over this, over the other side of the table.
一台悬浮式便携显示器
And this guy, he had these sunglasses on, but they were like out, like really far out of his head.
我正后悔自己的做法，突然发现
And I was like, Oh, that's weird. And he
对面戴着超夸张太阳镜的男子
kept looking over at my screen. I was like, Oh, he likes my screen.
眼镜下藏着特殊镜片
And then I looked closer and he had these like weird little lenses under the sunglasses. And
原来他戴着虚拟现实眼镜
I realised, Oh, they're virtual reality tech glasses. And he was doing all this head movements
他不断调整头部动作
in the cafe of like looking over there, looking down here, like interacting with the technology.
与咖啡馆内的全息投影技术互动
And so I just thought maybe we could put a pair of glasses on
这让我想到或许可以推出配套的VR眼镜
and get the food in front of us. This is the future. Yeah.
就能将食物呈现在我们面前。这就是未来啊。
That you'll get virtual food sort of like
你将获得类似全息投影在桌面上的虚拟食物。
a holograms on your table. And you can imagine, Hmm, do I like,
在餐桌上看到全息投影的牛排薯条，我会喜欢吗？嗯，这种情况我会满意吗？嗯，好吧。
am I happy with this situation with this plate of steak and chips on my plate? Hmm. Yeah.
看起来还不错。好的，我要这个。
It looks pretty good. Yeah. I'll have that please.
或者右滑左滑，左滑右滑。就能看到不同食物的模拟展示。
Or swipe right, swipe left, kind of swipe right, swipe left. And you get the different,
你可以看到食物的立体模拟效果。
you get a little simulation of the food in front of you. Yeah.
这应该是未来的餐饮方式吧，查理。
Well, this is probably the future,
这可能很酷。另外想到件事，寿司列车。
Charlie. That could be cool. Another thing I just thought, sushi trains.
我很喜欢寿司列车。真的超爱。圆盘式寿司店的情况。
I like them. Really like sushi trains. Sushi trains.
因为能看到完整制作过程。确实如此。我知道，我们说的所有问题，我早说会颠覆餐饮行业。
Yes. Yeah. The rotary sushi situation.
但现在旋转寿司餐厅已经解决了这个问题，对吧？没错，这太棒了。
Cause you get to see it. This is true. You know what? I think that all of the
我很喜欢那些餐厅。问题是它们能持续经营很久。
things we've been saying, I said it would break the restaurant trade.
比如像油炸蛋包饭这类寿司，只能保鲜一小时。没错，热汤类食物两分钟就凉了。
Uh, but now that of course the rotary sushi restaurant has
或者像热汤、洋葱汤这样需要保温的餐品。
already solved this problem. Hasn't it? Yeah. That is a wonderful thing.
两分钟后就会没人吃了。
I do love those, those restaurants. Yeah. Thing is it does last quite well.
所以 yeah，有些食物可能适用。
So yeah. Whereas like a fried egg or something sushi belt for about an hour. Yeah, that's right.
可能只是单程轨道，列车到站后直接进入垃圾桶。现在就能取餐。
Or something that should be hot, like a good sort of like plate of hot soup,
嗯，没错。您要是不吃的话，就会被扔掉哦。
onion soup or something that's really hot. Uh, yeah, yeah. It's like after two minutes,
或者右滑左滑，左滑右滑。就能看到不同食物的模拟展示。
it's like, well, no one's going to eat that now.
你可以看到食物的立体模拟效果。
Um, yeah, yeah, of course. Maybe it works for certain food. Yeah.
这应该是未来的餐饮方式吧，查理。
Maybe it's like just one, it's not even a loop. It's one train and it
这可能很酷。另外想到件事，寿司列车。
goes into the bin. Like you can grab it now.
我很喜欢寿司列车。真的超爱。圆盘式寿司店的情况。
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
因为能看到完整制作过程。确实如此。我知道，我们说的所有问题，我早说会颠覆餐饮行业。
Yeah. And it's on your head. You know, if you don't eat this, it's going to get chucked away.
但现在旋转寿司餐厅已经解决了这个问题，对吧？没错，这太棒了。
And so it's like the restaurant, um, holds no accountability for this.
这家餐厅对此事概不负责。
It's the customer's fault. If there's a lot of waste at the end of the evening.
问题在顾客自身。如果晚上剩菜太多就是他们的错。
Um, yeah. Uh, on the subject of like different types of menus, I'm sure that in other parts of
关于菜单类型，我觉得在其他地方这很常见，比如菜单配图。
the world, it's kind of a bit more normal to have photos on menus. I think that especially
现在用iPad等设备做菜单已经很普遍了，高档餐厅会用带精美图片的平板或设备。
these days with the iPads and stuff, there will be, there will be like high level, high class
我猜想现在肯定有人在听，但在我所在的城市，菜单上配图的大餐厅其实并不罕见。
restaurants with like menus on iPads or, you know, devices, which have wonderful pictures on them.
的确如此，上周我去了一家艺术感十足的美味餐厅，他们的菜单本身就是品牌故事。
I'm just imagining there's probably someone listening to this going, but in my town,
不仅有品牌理念介绍，还有主厨个人故事和招牌菜特色。
there is, there are plenty of amazing restaurants with pictures on the menus.
每页都是全幅高清招牌菜图，我直接买了一份当艺术品。
Uh, that's probably is the case in some places. Um, yes, actually I went to a, um,
全幅印刷？我原以为这是指人失血过多死亡......原来我理解错了啊。
I went to one yesterday and it was a beautifully done artistic sort of storytelling menu.
全幅印刷就是印刷到页面边缘，不留边距对吧？
And it was like telling about their brand, what they believe in, and then the, the,
意思是说油墨会完全渗透到纸张边缘。
the chef themselves and then what dishes they really like. And it was a full bleed
对，这样图片就占满整张纸了。
picture of the signature dish. And I got it because it looked amazing.
我这就明白啦，上周那家餐厅的菜单就是这样印刷的。
Full bleed. Does that mean like full size? I think so. I don't know what that means.
真的是完美呈现，这种设计确实让人印象深刻。
Full bleed. I thought it's just when you know, you,
这说明另一个世界是存在的，查理。
you, you, you, you die because you lost a lot of blood. Um, that's what I thought.
你眼前展现的是更美好的可能，这就是你渴望生活的世界。
It's like that. I don't want that in a restaurant. No.
的确如此，上周我去了一家艺术感十足的美味餐厅，他们的菜单本身就是品牌故事。
Yeah. Full bleed printing means to the edge. Oh, I see.
不仅有品牌理念介绍，还有主厨个人故事和招牌菜特色。
So it's printed all the way to the edge of the page. There's no,
每页都是全幅高清招牌菜图，我直接买了一份当艺术品。
there's no border around it. So the picture takes up the entire page, right? It's called full bleed.
全幅印刷？我原以为这是指人失血过多死亡......原来我理解错了啊。
The ink bled all the way to the edges of the page. Yeah. I see.
全幅印刷就是印刷到页面边缘，不留边距对吧？
Yes. And yeah. And it looked great.
意思是说油墨会完全渗透到纸张边缘。
I had it and it was great. I thought that's it. So this is possible.
对，这样图片就占满整张纸了。
Another world is, is possible. You've got a glimpse of another better world,
我这就明白啦，上周那家餐厅的菜单就是这样印刷的。
Charlie. And you thought this is what, this is the world I want to live in.
真的是完美呈现，这种设计确实让人印象深刻。
Enough of these paper menus with written words. Yeah. The downside though, I will add is,
不再使用这些纸质菜单上的文字。 yeah. 但我还要补充的是，
as I said, Stacey, she comes from a background of food and, and chefing.
正如您所说，Stacey，她有餐饮和厨师行业的背景。
Um, and she said, yeah, but if you do commit to something like that,
嗯，她说，如果你确定做这类东西，
you can't change your menu very often. And there's a lot of other
就不能频繁更换菜单。还有很多其他
marketing that comes into it and lots of costs. So you'd be paying for it.
市场营销需要投入，花费也不少。所以你不得不支付这些费用。
Cause it printing costs of photography costs and stuff for each time you change the menu.
因为你每次改菜单都要支付印刷成本和摄影费用什么的。
Whereas yeah. Otherwise you can just type one out and print it off and it's pretty simple.
而如果是电子版的话，直接打出来打印就很简单。
So we would be paying for it, but you know, if they didn't put the currency with the number,
所以我们虽然要付这些费用，但要是没标注货币单位，
we'd be fine. We'd be fine with it. That's right.
我们就无所谓。没问题。没错。
Um, I mean, I sort of understand the art, the concept of, uh, using sometimes language and
嗯，我的意思是，我理解这种艺术概念，就是
written language doesn't do the job. Uh, you know, you can't, it's like, uh, what is it talking about
有时语言文字确实难以尽述。就像
food maybe is like dancing about architecture. Have you heard that comparison made before? I
你无法用语言描述音乐，就像用舞蹈描述建筑一样。你听过这种类比吗？我记得好像是David Bowie说的，或者他引用别人的观点。
think it was like maybe David Bowie or someone who said this, or he quoted it from someone else.
你无法谈论音乐，就像谈论音乐本身就不可能，谈论艺术也不可能，但总会有局限。我们缺乏语言 richness 和灵活性去准确描述音乐。
You can't talk about music. Like talking about music is impossible or talking about art is
所以谈论音乐就像用舞蹈描述建筑。好吧。这种表达方式
impossible, but it always falls short language. We don't have the, um, you know, the richness,
永远无法像语言那样完整传达另一种艺术形式。就像
the flexibility of language to be able to do justice to the music we're trying to describe.
语言无法描述音乐，舞蹈也无法传达建筑所承载的概念。 yeah，这个类比很棒。
So talking about music is, is like dancing about architecture. Okay. That one method
是个不错的例子，刚开始看有点费解，
of communication, uh, can never, um, uh, really describe another, you know, that in
但仔细想想确实有道理。 yeah.
the same way that language can't describe music, dancing could never somehow get across the idea
但这不是要进 room 101，Charlie。抱歉。纸质菜单会保留的。
of something that you could communicate through architecture, you know? Yeah, that's, that's nice.
等等。不是纸质菜单，是。
A good example. It did make me go slightly cross-eyed at the beginning,
是书面菜单。好吧。 okay。
but yeah, it makes sense. Yeah.
你无法谈论音乐，就像谈论音乐本身就不可能，谈论艺术也不可能，但总会有局限。我们缺乏语言 richness 和灵活性去准确描述音乐。
But it's not going into room 101, Charlie. Sorry. Paper menus, um, are going to stay, um, and, uh.
所以谈论音乐就像用舞蹈描述建筑。好吧。这种表达方式
Hang on. It's not, it's not paper menus. It's.
永远无法像语言那样完整传达另一种艺术形式。就像
Well, written menus. Okay. Okay.
语言无法描述音乐，舞蹈也无法传达建筑所承载的概念。 yeah，这个类比很棒。
Yeah. Written menus, words,
好的。书面菜单，文字，
menus based mainly on the written word that they're going to stay. I'm sorry.
完全依赖文字的菜单将长期存在。抱歉。
And again, I refer to your wife, girlfriend, girlfriend, wife, partner, wife, wife,
且再次提到，关于您妻子、女友、伴侣、妻子、妻子，
your wife. Um, that this is true that if we got rid of them, then restaurants would have
您的妻子。嗯，如果撤掉她们（的人像），餐厅就得花费大量资金，
to spend a lot of money, print taking expensive photos and printing them and, you know, paying,
拍摄昂贵的照片、印刷、支付，
shelling out lots of money for full bleed, uh, photographs on their menus. Um, and so, no, sorry.
大量支出购买全幅（照片）印刷在菜单上。嗯，所以，不，抱歉。
We're just going to stick with the written word. Um, in this instance, Charlie. Fair enough.
我们还是坚持用文字说明。嗯，这个要求，Charlie，可以理解。
Again, I'll let you, I'll let you innovate something. I'll let you innovate,
再说一遍，我会让你们自己，
um, a better solution and get back to us on that one. Yes.
想出更好的解决方案，并反馈给我们。好的。
Okay. Yeah. I'll have a think.
好的。我考虑考虑。
Fair enough. Oh, was that two of three? That was three of three. So as in, uh,
可以理解。刚才说的是三个中的两个吗？三个都完成了。那就像在101房间，
did I get two out of three in room 101? You've got two out of three in room 101.
我是否拿到两个对三个？你们在101房间拿了两个对三个。
So the things that went in, the first one was a toilet roll dispensers that
进101房间的物品：第一个是不透明的纸巾架，
are not see-through. Um, because you know, none of us want to be in
因为我们都不想陷入您当时的困境。这样对所有人更安全。
the same predicament you were in. So I think it's better, safer for everyone.
如果这些放进101房间，第二个问题是，
If, if those go into room 101, second thing was, uh, Lucy from English with Lucy not
Lucy（来自英语系）的厨房里只有速溶咖啡，
having anything other than instant coffee in her kitchen when guests,
或者在客人来时（或您来访时）。这也要进101房间。
or maybe when just you come to her house. So that's in room 101. Lucy's got to up her game,
Lucy需要在家庭咖啡设施上升级。
raise her game in terms of coffee making facilities at home.
第三点是，等等，我有点混乱了，第三个是什么？是的。
And the third thing, uh, is, um, wait a minute. I'm confused that the third thing is. Yeah.
第三个就是菜单。没错。
The third is the menus. Yeah. Yeah.
对，所以我们在101房间拿到两个对三个。没错。
Yeah. So we got two out of three in room 101. Oh yeah.
对，刚才第二个问题，抱歉，是速溶咖啡，
So the second one, sorry, was instant coffee,
但因为太方便了，不会放进101房间。Charlie，我现在多混乱？
which is not going to go into room 101 because it's just too convenient. Uh, but I will,
我现在真的有点混乱。是的。
um, how confused am I, Charlie? I'm really confused at this point. Yeah.
或者在客人来时（或您来访时）。这也要进101房间。
So you're, you're, um, giving me a specific thing
你是在我第二个案例中给了我一个具体的东西
within my second case that will go in room 101, which is the hosting,
要放进101号房间的，是关于 hosting（主办）规则和接受某些程度的 hosting 的内容。不过
uh, sort of rules and acceptance of certain levels of hosting that should go in. But that,
但速溶咖啡就不放进去了，因为你已经有了，还在用嘛。不过我算是给你个甜头，对吧？
but instant coffee's not going in because you've got instant coffee. You use it.
你也给我了甜头。所以你在101号房间给了我1.5分，我就按这个算吧。
It's not going in, but I, I, I kind of, um, yeah, threw you a bone in the sense that. Yes. Yeah.
我是不是给了？因为纸质菜单也不放进去了，就这些。
You threw me a bone. And so you gave me one and a half out of three in room 101. Let's say I did.
书面菜单都不放。我很高兴我们搞定了这个。你帮我保持了短期记忆。
Did I kind of, uh, yeah. Cause paper menus are not going in. That's it.
非常感谢。呃，查理，这真的很开心。
Uh, written menus, written menus are not going in. I'm
我确实很享受这次对话。当然，我会在你们的播客上做同样的事情，列出三个要点。
glad we sorted that out. You helped me with my short term memory there.
我们已经录制好了，现在就发布，因为同期制作这些内容，所以现在就能收听。
Thanks a lot. Um, all right, Charlie. Well, this is really good fun.
听众如果想了解我想被放逐到101号房间的三个物品，可以听这个节目。
Um, and I enjoyed this a lot. And of course, uh, I was on,
大家怎么找到这个期节目？在YouTube的英式英语播客，或者任何播客应用、Spotify，我还会上传视频。
I, I will be on your podcast doing exactly the same thing. Um, naming my three things.
总之，英式英语播客在各大平台都有。这期内容很精彩，你提出了三个有趣选项，探讨起来很有趣。
Uh, we've already recorded that. That's it. That's available now because we're
我强烈推荐大家收听。不过，非常感谢。不客气。
publishing these during the, in the same week so that that will be available now.
对了，你之前提到现在住在葡萄牙波尔图，是从澳洲搬到伦敦，再转到葡萄牙的。能简单说说这个过程吗？
So if listeners want to know what I, uh, wanted to be banished into room one and one, they
上次聊天时你住在澳洲，后来搬到伦敦，再从伦敦到葡萄牙。当时是怎么考虑的？
can listen to it. Uh, what's the best way for people to find that episode? Yeah. On YouTube,
书面菜单都不放。我很高兴我们搞定了这个。你帮我保持了短期记忆。
the British English podcast or any podcast app, Spotify, or I also upload video.
非常感谢。呃，查理，这真的很开心。
So yeah, anywhere and everywhere, the British English podcast. And it was a
我确实很享受这次对话。当然，我会在你们的播客上做同样的事情，列出三个要点。
really good one. You, you brought up three nice options, which were fun to go through.
我们已经录制好了，现在就发布，因为同期制作这些内容，所以现在就能收听。
So I highly recommend it. But yeah, thank you very much. You're welcome.
听众如果想了解我想被放逐到101号房间的三个物品，可以听这个节目。
Um, just before you go, uh, so you talked earlier about how, at the moment you live in,
大家怎么找到这个期节目？在YouTube的英式英语播客，或者任何播客应用、Spotify，我还会上传视频。
in Portugal, you recently moved to, to Porto in Portugal. Can you just tell me
总之，英式英语播客在各大平台都有。这期内容很精彩，你提出了三个有趣选项，探讨起来很有趣。
a few things about the move? So I think last time I spoke to you on this podcast,
我强烈推荐大家收听。不过，非常感谢。不客气。
you lived in Australia, but you moved from Australia to London and then from London
对了，你之前提到现在住在葡萄牙波尔图，是从澳洲搬到伦敦，再转到葡萄牙的。能简单说说这个过程吗？
to Portugal. So can you just tell us about how that happened? Yeah.
上次聊天时你住在澳洲，后来搬到伦敦，再从伦敦到葡萄牙。当时是怎么考虑的？
Yeah. I mean, we've jumped around quite a bit now because we've done five or six different countries
嗯，我们这十五年确实跑了不少国家，做了五六个国家的项目
over the last 15 years. And, um, we've done it in like three year stints, three to four year stints.
而且每次都是三到四年一个周期地轮换
So we did Australia, and then we came back to London. Um, I think London has
比如我们先去澳大利亚，然后回到伦敦
a lot to offer. It's got everything, but it's not quite suiting our lifestyle.
伦敦什么都有，但不太符合我们的生活节奏
So, uh, after three years of trialling that, we thought,
尝试了三年后我们认为
okay, we're done with that. We'll move on. And we are thinking about making a family,
这条路走到头了，该换个方向了
uh, and we want to be around Stacey's family for support and, you know, to be around them.
我们现在考虑组建家庭
That'd be lovely to be around them, of course. And food. Yeah.
希望能靠近斯泰西的家人获得支持
Um, so we will probably go back over there, which is Worcester. We'll probably live in Worcester,
而且还要考虑饮食因素
but between London and Worcester, we thought, well, let's have some fun in different cities
所以我们可能搬去伍斯特
before we need to go over there. Uh, and we wanted to escape the winter.
但在定居前想多体验几个城市
So, uh, we thought, well, let's go down to the bottom part of Europe
逃离英国冬季是个重要考量
where it's not that far down, but it's a bit further down.
所以计划南下欧洲
And we thought we've had, we've heard great things about Portugal. Generally we've been
选个不太远但能避寒的地方
to Lisbon and we heard Porto is like a smaller, less expensive version of Lisbon.
我们之前对葡萄牙有很好的印象
So we were like, it'd be great. And they were like, and it's really digital nomad friendly. So,
已去过里斯本，波尔图据说是更小更实惠的版本
um, yeah, my wife also works online, so we're able to move around quite freely now.
听说那里对数字游民很友好
And, uh, yeah, so we packed up our house in London and, uh, sent my in-laws with a
我们妻子也做线上工作
load of stuff to Worcester. And then we took the essentials in our car, which was our sausage dog,
现在能灵活辗转各地
two suitcases each and, uh, my piano. So we actually took my piano in the car.
所以我们打包了伦敦的房子
It's a, it's a electric piano. It's a Roland FP 10. I don't know if you know the models.
让公婆带着大部分行李去了伍斯特
No, I don't know that particular one. I think, but okay. But it's just, you know,
我们自己开车带着必需品
it's, it's more substantial than a keyboard, but not a full blown piano.
包括我的香肠犬、两个行李箱
Uh, but yeah, so we took that and loads of other stuff and my
还有我的钢琴——
gear as well. That's accumulated over the years. Um, audio gear.
一台Roland FP 10电钢琴
Yeah. And, uh, and then, um, yeah, we, we drove all the way from London to
嗯。然后我们开车从伦敦一路开了到波尔图。
Porto. So we got in the Euro tunnel train, which I found fascinating.
我们坐了欧洲隧道列车，我觉得特别有意思。
I've never done that before. I went through the, I did, I've done the,
我以前没坐过这个。虽然多次坐过渡轮过海，但你们坐过带车的火车吗？
um, ferry crossing multiple times, but have you done the train in a car? It's amazing,
真神奇，不是吗？你开着车开上火车，然后在火车里坐着车过海隧道。
isn't it? Cause you, you sit in the car, you drive, you drive the car onto a train and then
我当时车后座还带着自行车。所以我在海底隧道里坐着带自行车的车。
the train you sit in the car. So you're in a car on a train in a tunnel under the sea.
顶层海轮从头顶驶过，我们就在海轮下方。
Um, when I did it, I had my bike in the back of the car as well. So I had my bike
看着海轮从头顶掠过，确实挺刺激的。就坐在火车里看隧道过去。
in a car on a train in a tunnel under the sea. There were probably boats going over the top.
然后火车到达另一端，我们开车下车，就到法国了。
So under boats, you know, um, yeah, it's exciting. You just sit in the car going
那边有标准款手风琴，人们啃法棍面包，有人耸耸肩。
through the tunnel on the train and then you arrive at the other
真是无惊无险又令人兴奋的经历。就坐在车里看混凝土墙飞速掠过。
side and you drive off the train and there you are in France. Yeah.
但这种穿越海底列车的概念确实很有趣。
There's the standard accordions,
进站时确实有点疯狂，不是很刺激吗？
people eating baguettes and stuff and people shrugging their shoulders. Yeah,
六岁男孩在车里肯定特别开心，想开车上火车。
exactly. It's the most uneventful, exciting thing I've ever done, I think.
是啊，这确实是既平淡又刺激的经历。
Cause you're just in a car. You're just, you can't even see out. That's it.
因为你完全看不到外面，只能看着混凝土墙飞驰而过。
It's just concrete going past you really quickly. Yeah. But
但这种过海列车的概念确实很有趣。
the idea of it is quite, quite, quite fun.
驾车进站的过程确实很疯狂，不是很刺激吗？
And driving into the train was quite mad. It's exciting, isn't it? Yeah. The six year old,
六岁男孩的视角一定特别兴奋，想开车上火车。
the six year old boy inside you is just absolutely delighted at the idea of driving onto a train.
的确如此，我侄子们就迷这些小挖掘机。
Yeah, it really is that, isn't it? Cause I see my nephews,
他们的脑子似乎天生就对这些有执念。
they're just so obsessed with little diggers and little like construction things. They're just,
这其实都是我们童年的天性。
their brain is so wired to be obsessive over it. And it is the child in us that likes it.
我儿子性别认同方面有些特别，虽然社会常说男孩女孩喜欢不同东西。
It's my son. He's, I mean, you know, you know, gender identity and stuff. And,
我们没有特别强调这些性别刻板印象，
you know, people say, oh, boys are into these things and girls are into these things.
但确实观察到这种现象。
We didn't really particularly put, I think,
是啊，这确实是既平淡又刺激的经历。
push our daughter towards ponies and horses and unicorns, uh, or,
我们让女儿接触小马驹和骏马以及独角兽，呃，或者
and sort of like encourage our son to be into trains and trucks and stuff. But that's exactly
大致鼓励儿子热衷于火车和卡车之类的东西。但那正是
what they're both like. And he's two and he will just spend an hour just building stuff.
他们俩的现状。他现在两岁，会花一个小时搭积木。
He just gets all his toy cars and puts them all in a big line. And, you know,
他把所有玩具车排成一条直线。你知道的，
that's a garage and he just loves making garages and you'll, you'll just build train tracks out of,
这是个车库，他最爱搭车库，还会用乐高火车套装之类的
you know, Lego train sets and stuff. And you'll just do that.
材料铺铁轨。你就是要这么做。
I mean, if you, if you try and stop him, it's just all hell breaks loose. It's like, no, I must
意思是如果你试图阻止他，天都要塌了。不行，我必须
be allowed to construct this large garage with a, with a little train train track on the side. Yeah.
在这个带小火车轨道的侧边搭个大型车库。嗯。
But what about your sister's lovely pink doll? No, no, only, only diggers. Yeah. Yeah.
但你妹妹可爱的粉红洋娃娃呢？不，不，只准玩挖掘机。嗯。嗯。
It is mad. It is mad. Yeah.
真疯狂。真疯狂。嗯。
I think. Yeah. But yeah.
我想。嗯。但 yeah。
So, um, so we got off the train and then we,
我们下了火车，接着
we drove three days through Europe. It was delightful. We had a, an Airbnb in each spot.
在欧洲开了三天车。真开心。我们在每个地方都订了Airbnb。
We, we went from Calais to Limon to Bordeaux to Biritz to Lyon and then,
从加来开到里姆昂，再开到波尔多，开到比里茨，开到里昂，最后
um, Porto. It was great. Wow.
到了波尔图。太棒了。哇。
Yeah. Yeah. Great, great road trip.
嗯。嗯。太棒的公路旅行。
Um, so, uh, so yeah, you wanted to leave London. You wanted to try and escape the wet wintery,
嗯，所以你想离开伦敦，想逃离伦敦阴雨连绵的冬季天气，
the wet weather of London and you arrived in Porto and it has not stopped raining. Goodness me.
到了波尔图却没停过雨。天啊。
I've never seen anything quite like this in Australia. It used to rain
在澳大利亚我从未见过这种天气。以前最多连续十天下雨，
occasionally for 10 days straight and it was really hard, but we've been here,
非常难熬。但我们已经待了整整一个月，
I think a whole month now. And I, I don't think I've seen a day without rain yet.
直到现在，我觉得还没见过没下雨的一天。
It's been every day, really, really strong winds,
几乎每天都是狂风暴雨，
horrendous rain. I think what satisfies me is when we get into a taxi and they're like, yeah, this,
倾盆大雨。让我安慰的是，每次坐出租车，司机都会说
we've never seen this before. Or they're like, I don't remember a time that it was this wet.
“ yeah，这我们可没见过”或者“我不记得曾经这么潮湿过”。
Cause if it was like, oh yeah, this is winter. I'd be like,
要是像这样的话——嗯，哦，这就是冬天——我可能会说，
I'm an idiot. What am I thinking? But apparently it's unprecedented.
我真是个蠢货。我在想什么？不过看起来这前所未有的。
So I can't, I can't judge that. I, you know, I can't play God. No,
所以我不能评头论足。我，你知道的，我不能玩弄上帝。不，
just pure bad luck on your part there that you escaped rain and you just got more rain.
那只是你运气不好。你躲过了一次雨，却紧接着又下起了大雨。
Um, it's going to improve. It's got to improve. It literally has to improve.
呃，情况会好转的。必须好转。 literally 得好转。
Like there's no worse than this. There's been trees down. There's been power cuts.
没有比这更糟的了。树木被连根拔起。断电事故频发。
There's been deaths. I think even, yeah. Man.
更别提人员伤亡了。是的。男人。
Nightmare. Yeah. Okay.
噩梦啊…好吧。
Well, good luck. I hope that the rains,
祝你好运。希望这场持续四十天四十夜的暴雨结束。希望你的方舟顺利建造完成。
the 40 days and 40 nights of rain end. I hope you got your, your arc sorted out.
你已经建好方舟了？不知道上帝有没有告诉你这个？我还没收到消息。
You got, you've built an arc. I don't know if God told you about that. I haven't yet.
没收到通知。嗯，这话听起来有点冒犯，
I didn't get the message. No, that's a bit rude,
不是吗？你认识诺亚吗？不巧得很。
isn't it? You don't know anyone called Noah. Do you? Funny chance.
如果认识的话，或许可以试试这样喊一嗓子："诺亚！"
If you do, you might want to just like, Hey, Noah,
你正在建造方舟对吧？有没有可能我的妻子和我——还有我的香肠狗，
uh, see you're building an arc there. Any chance that my wife and I could, uh, and my sausage dog,
里面有两只香肠狗吗？不，抱歉。动物要成双成对进入。
he's like, are there two sausage dogs in that? No, sorry. Animals go in two by two.
你没听过这首歌吗？确实有两只，
Did you not hear the song? Yeah, there are two,
但都是母的。我们遇到问题了。我们遇到问题了。
but they're both female. We've got a problem. We've got a problem.
我一直没完全搞懂诺亚方舟的故事。整体逻辑和后勤安排，
I've never fully understood the story of Noah's arc, the general logic and
但这留到下次再聊吧，不是吗？呃，查理，
logistics of it, but that's another story for another time, isn't it? Um, Charlie,
谢谢再次参加播客。玩得开心。还有101号房间。
thanks for coming on the podcast again. It was really good fun. And, uh, room 101.
为新一期节目想出这么好的创意。不错。确实。
What a nice idea for, for an episode. Nice one. Yeah, it's good.
感谢您邀请我。非常荣幸。确实。
Thank you very much for having me. It was a pleasure. Yeah, indeed.
好吧，伙计。祝你好运。
Indeed. All right, mate. Well, good luck.
希望你周末愉快，云开雾散，阳光重现。
I hope you have a reasonable weekend and that the clouds part and the sun comes
明天确实会有晴天图标。自来到这里以来还是头一遭。
out. We do have a sunny icon tomorrow. It's the first time since coming here.
你正在建造方舟对吧？有没有可能我的妻子和我——还有我的香肠狗，
So thank you. Yeah, I will enjoy it. Brilliant.
谢谢。是的，我会享受的。太棒了。
Brilliant. Okay, mate. Yeah.
太棒了。好吧，老兄。嗯。
Enjoy. Have a good one. I hear Paris is better, right? Um,
享受吧。祝你一切顺利。听说巴黎更好，对吧？呃，
what better than, but in terms of weather at the moment, yeah, the weather's okay.
不错，但就当前天气而言，嗯，天气还不错。
I mean, it's just sort of like, uh, it's like England. It's like London. It's it rains,
意思是说，它就像英格兰，像伦敦，下雨后停了太阳就出来，又下雨。
then it stops and the sun comes out and it rains again.
你知道，天气差不多像伦敦。
You know, it's more or less the same weather as it is in London. In fact, I've heard statistically
事实上统计数据显示
Paris gets more millimetres of rain than London does, but no one ever talks about that. Do they
巴黎的毫米降雨量比伦敦多，但没人提这个。真的吗？
somehow Paris still has this represent rep reputation of Paris in the spring and
毕竟巴黎总保持着春日花海、蓝天白云和街边休憩的浪漫形象
the flowers are blooming and the sky is blue and everyone's sitting around on pavements and stuff.
而伦敦总被说阴雨连绵，但我觉得
Um, but London's the one that everyone says is rainy all the time, but I think I would guess
我没住过那里。所以，可能更好，但估计伦敦更常是灰蒙蒙的
I haven't lived there. So, you know, better, but I would guess London is more just constantly grey
而巴黎会下阵雨，降雨量累积更快，但阳光更充足。
and drizzle. Whereas Paris gets showers, gets the millimetres up, but there's more sunshine hours.
是的。比如这里下雨时
Yeah. Something like that. Or when it rains here, it really rains.
就像暂停键。没错。
It's sort of like pause. Yeah. Exactly.
正好相反，在英格兰
Yeah. Um, whereas in England, it's just like, well, let's just drizzle
我们只会下会儿细雨，然后持续降雨
for a while and we'll just rain, but we're not going to rain that heavily,
但不会下得特别猛
but it will be wet and depressing. Whereas in Paris it's like, okay, so we rain now.
但会让人生无可恋
Okay. Let's do it. And you just get loads of rain and
而巴黎会说好，现在开始下雨
then it stops and it's quite sunny for a while.
好的，来场大雨
So when it rains, it rains more heavily maybe. And whereas in England,
然后突然停了
it's just a general sort of drizzly nightmare for about six months. Yeah.
接着阳光持续一段时间
Yeah. Yeah, exactly. Yeah.
所以巴黎下雨更猛，但持续时间短
Yeah. All right. Listen, we must end this conversation sooner or later.
而英格兰有半年时间
We might as well do it now. Uh, lovely to talk to you and,
整天阴雨连绵的噩梦。嗯。
uh, speak to you again soon, mate. Likewise.
嗯，改天再聊，兄弟。 likewise.
Take care. Bye. Right.
多保重。嗯，再见。
So that is the end of that. Thank you again to Charlie for being the guest on the show,
这就是故事的终点了。再次感谢Charlie作为本集嘉宾，
uh, for this one listeners. I really hope you enjoyed that.
感谢各位听众收听本集节目，希望你们都听得尽兴。
Uh, how was that for you? I'm always curious to know, uh, how it was for you. So leave
你觉得如何？我一直好奇你的感受，所以
your comments in the comment section. Did you understand the basics? Did you understand the
请在评论区留下反馈。是否掌握了基本要点？是否理解了基本概念？
basic things? Obviously the, the three things, the first one was toilet roll dispensers,
显然有三个要点，第一个是卷纸盒，
where you can't see how much toilet roll is actually in the dispenser.
你无法直接看到盒内实际剩余的卷纸量。
And Charlie told this story of how he had an unfortunate under,
Charlie讲述了他不幸运的经历——
he had an unfortunate incident with his underpants because he ate something that
因吃了不洁食物导致肠胃不适，
gave him a bad stomach and he had to go to the toilet, but he wasn't able to go there
但他在妻子使用公共厕所时坚持为女士开门，
in time because he was being such a gentleman and holding the door of a public toilet for
结果耽误了如厕时间。
his wife while she was using it. Um, and he, he had no choice. He had to go right there.
他别无选择，只能当场解决。
I mean, I won't go into the details, but I think you understand that he
我不细说细节，但相信你理解他发生了什么。
had an accident in his underpants. And then he went into this electronic toilet, which,
内裤突然出现意外状况。此时正值如厕时，
um, went into cleaning mode while he was in there trying to do his business. The,
智能马桶自动开启清洁模式，
the toilet suddenly started spraying him with water and soap and stuff.
突然开始喷水、肥皂和清洁剂。
It sounds like a nightmare, but the, the, the final straw, the last straw,
这听起来像场噩梦，但关键转折点发生在
um, was that when he finally went to get toilet paper from the toilet paper dispenser, he wasn't
他最后取纸时发现——
aware that there were only a few pieces of paper left. And of course he, he used, as he said,
卷纸盒仅剩少量纸巾。
about 10% of how much he actually needed. Um, and so that was obviously a terrible disaster for him.
正如您所说，他仅使用了所需量的10%。
And he focused all his attention on the fact that he couldn't see how much toilet roll was in there.
这显然是一场灾难。问题核心在于：
So he was unable to judge, you know, how much, how economical he had to be with the paper. I agreed.
由于卷纸盒不透明设计，
I said, I sympathised with him and agreed. And so the opaque toilet roll dispensers,
他无法准确判断该用多少纸，
uh, went into room one Oh one, the second one, this is where the drama could come from. Right.
因此无法做到合理节约用纸。我深表同情，并附议：第一种改进方案应设为透明卷纸盒，
And Charlie told a shocking story of how he was invited to Lucy's house, which is somewhere in
查理讲述了他被邀请去露西家的震惊故事，那座位于英格兰乡村的房子似乎离商店等设施很远。
the English countryside, um, apparently quite far away from shops and things like that. So anyways,
不管怎样，他正在前往妻子家，又或者说前往公婆家的路上。他们中途去拜访了露西，但露西的丈夫是谁？我记不清了。
he was on his way to his wife's on his way to his parents-in-law's house. They stopped
我记得他们应该是夫妻关系。是的，他们确实是。不是吗？所以他们是顺道去拜访了。
off to see Lucy and will that's Lucy's husband is they married? I can't remember.
看起来挺不错的，去露西家看看，就在他们家对吧？Charlie却大吃一惊——露西给他倒了速溶咖啡。
Um, I think they are. Yeah, they are. Aren't they? So they dropped in on that.
当然我们都惊呆了。互联网也会被震撼的，因为我们觉得露西家应该有专业的咖啡制作设备。
It sounds lovely, you know, a nice trip to, to see Lucy and will, uh, is it will, I think it is,
你会想她的厨房肯定配备着顶级的咖啡机吧？
uh, at their house, but Charlie was shocked that Lucy gave him a cup of instant coffee instant.
的确如此。但Charlie端到的却是速溶咖啡，他至今难忘。
And of course, we're all shocked. The internet's going to be shocked by this because we all look
我记得这还是两年前的事，他一直记着这件事。
at Lucy and we think there's someone who's got top level coffee making facilities in her home.
他选择用这个平台散布这种恶意八卦，
Her kitchen is going to have an excellent coffee maker in
哦，这算不算要引发连锁反应？
it. You'd imagine she's going to have some good quality coffee,
Lucy 因此会被取消吗？
right? That you understand, right? Of course, Lucy's going to have good coffee,
所有人都会说“再也不看她的视频了”。
but Charlie was given a cup of instant coffee and he has never forgotten. He's it's up.
她居然只喝速溶咖啡？
I got the impression. It was a couple of years ago, even, and Charlie's been holding onto this
这可能成为转折点。我不确定。
information all this time. And he was so shocked, but he has, he chose to use this platform as his,
Anyway，这事儿明确是关于Lucy Earl（来自英格兰的那个露西），
um, as his platform to spread this gossip, this malicious gossip, um, which could, I mean,
她连客人或查理都只能提供速溶咖啡，
is this going to bring this? Is this the end? Is Lucy going to get cancelled as a result of this?
而这已进入“房间101”（注：指节目中的禁忌清单）。
Everyone's going to be like, I'm not listening to, I'm not going to watch Lucy's videos anymore.
我很好奇露西会不会看到这段。
She just drinks instant coffee. Maybe this is going to be a turning point. I don't know.
我在想，要不要把邮件发给她？我好像有她邮箱地址。
But anyway, it was specifically, we decided it was specifically Lucy Earl from English with Lucy,
发还是不发呢？
not having anything better than instant coffee to provide to guests or maybe just Charlie.
或许我应该等等，看她自己会不会发现。
And that went into room 101. Um, I wonder if Lucy's ever going to, ever going to see this.
哦，这算不算要引发连锁反应？
Um, I've just been thinking, should I, should I send this to her? I'm pretty sure I've got her
Lucy 因此会被取消吗？
email address. Shall I send this to her? I don't know. I think maybe what I'm going to do is I'm
所有人都会说“再也不看她的视频了”。
going to, I'm going to wait and, and just see if she finds out about this, uh, independently.
她居然只喝速溶咖啡？
She probably won't because has she got the time to listen to this? I don't know, but there's probably
她可能没时间听这个，对吧？我不确定，但很可能
a good chance that she'll never discover this. Well, maybe someone's going to, maybe one of you
她永远发现不了这个。也许有人会，也许你们其中一位是Lucy的粉丝，会分享给她。我不确定。
is a follower of Lucy or something, and you're going to share this with her. I don't know.
不过如果她没发现的话，我可能也会分享给她，再添把火。
Uh, but if, if she never finds out that maybe I will share this with her and I'll stir things up
反正这都只是闹着玩的，对吧？真的假的？当然啦。
a bit. I mean, it's all a bit of a joke, isn't it? Really? Obviously. I mean, that's obvious.
就是这么一回事。
I don't need to say that, but you know, it's all just a bit of a laugh. Um,
我觉得这不算严肃的批评，不会对Lucy造成太大影响。我觉得她应该会觉得挺有趣的。
I don't think this is the sort of serious, uh, criticism that's going to, uh, really,
谁知道呢？或许我会给她公开回应的机会。她应该配得上这个吧？
uh, affect Lucy too much. I think she's going to find it all pretty funny to be honest.
或许我应该邀请Lucy上播客解释自己，为自己辩护？
Who knows? Maybe maybe I will, maybe I will give Lucy the right to reply. I think she,
这样才公平。对吧？让Lucy解释清楚才是公平竞争。
she deserves that much. Doesn't she? Maybe she gets, I should give her the right to reply.
但也许她会过于羞愧或愤怒，承受不了。
Maybe I should invite Lucy onto the podcast in order to explain herself,
我不知道。你呢？你觉得呢？
to defend herself, right? That would be, that would be equitable of me. Wouldn't
第三件事是带文字描述的菜单，用英文书面语描述，不是其他选项菜单。
it? That would be fair. That would be fair play to let Lucy explain herself,
这些菜单没进禁书室。
but maybe she's going to be just too ashamed or too offended or shocked and hurt.
我的菜单设计得很花哨，用无用的描述抬价，他们就能多收钱。
I don't know. Um, you can tell me, what do you think? But that went into room 101. And the
我本可以把这些菜单丢进禁书室，但实际呈现的是带文字描述的常规菜单。
third thing was, uh, menus where the food is described, uh, just in written English, uh,
这些菜单留在了正常范围内。
written language, uh, rather than any other kind of option menus, uh, with written descriptions.
以下是翻译要点：
And they, that did not go into room 101. Uh, I might've put pretentious
播客描述里有PDF字幕稿，记得查看。
menus with unhelpful descriptions that are designed just to kind of add value
是的，去听听我在《英国英语》播客上的表现吧。
to the food so they can charge you a lot more money than they should be. You know,
这样才公平。对吧？让Lucy解释清楚才是公平竞争。
I might add that into room 101, but that's not what was, what was presented.
但也许她会过于羞愧或愤怒，承受不了。
It was menus with written descriptions, uh, that they stay in the world. Okay.
我不知道。你呢？你觉得呢？
Um, PDF transcripts available, um, in the episode description, check it out.
第三件事是带文字描述的菜单，用英文书面语描述，不是其他选项菜单。
Okay. Um, yeah. All right then.
这些菜单没进禁书室。
And yes, go over and listen to, uh, my, um, appearance on the British English podcast
我的菜单设计得很花哨，用无用的描述抬价，他们就能多收钱。
and hear the things that I talked about. I had a really good time. I had a really,
听听我刚才提到的内容。我真的很享受这次交流。真的，
I had such a good time ranting about three things.
我聊了三件事，真的过得很愉快。
Um, I don't know if you're going to agree with me on my choices and my reasons for
嗯，我不确定你是否会认同我的选择及背后的理由。
choosing them. I think there's, there's, there's one that you are almost certain to
我想其中有一个观点你几乎肯定会同意。
agree with me on. There's one that I think will divide my audience.
还有一个我认为会引发听众分歧的观点。
Some of you will think, yeah, I agree with you, Luke. And some of you will be like,
部分听众会认同"卢克你讲得对"，部分则会质疑"这怎么可能"。
no way, man. Um, so you can find out by listening to the episode.
通过收听本期节目你可以验证这一点。
Uh, you'll find a link in the description, uh,
描述中会提供相关链接，也就是
otherwise the British English podcast. Okay. Nice one.
英国英语播客。好的。
Thanks for listening. Thanks for watching everybody. Leave
感谢收听。感谢观看的各位。
your comments in the comment section.
请在评论区留言互动。
Um, and have a lovely morning, afternoon, evening, or night,
祝你有个美好的早晨/下午/傍晚/夜晚，
wherever you are in the world, whatever you happen to be doing with yourself at
无论此刻你身处世界何处，正在做什么。
this moment in time. But until next time, I will just say good bye. Bye.
下次再会。再见。
Bye. Bye. Bye.
再见。再见。再见。